在很久的过去 能量体就已经存在了
Before time began, there was the Cube.
我们不知道它从哪里来
We know not where it comes from,
只知道它拥有…
only that it holds the power…
创造世界和生命的力量
to create worlds and fill them with life.
我们这个种族就是这么诞生的
That is how our race was born.
我们一直和谐地生活着
For a time, we lived in harmony,
就像其它巨大的能量一样
but like all great power,
人们要它的目的有善有恶
some wanted it for good, others for evil.
所以战争开始了
And so began the war,
一场使我们的星球…
a war that ravaged our planet…
毁灭的战争
until it was consumed by death,
能量体也丢失在浩瀚的宇宙里
and the Cube was lost to the far reaches of space.
我们搜寻了整个银河
We scattered across the galaxy,
希望可以找到它来重建我们的家园
hoping to find it and rebuild our home,
寻找每一个星球 每一个世界
searching every star, every world.
就当我们都失去希望时
And just when all hope seemed lost,
新的线索…
message of a new discovery…
把我们带到了一个星球叫做…
drew us to an unknown planet called
地球
Earth.
《变形金刚》
但是我们已经太迟了
But we were already too late.
（中东 卡塔尔 当代）
上帝啊 都已经5个月了
Oh, God, five months of this.
我都等不及要回家了
I can't wait to get a little taste of home
我很想念我妈妈煮的鳄鱼肉
A plate of mama's alligators touffe.
你说这些鳄鱼肉…
You've been talking about barbecued 'gators…
都说了2个星期了
and crickets for the last two weeks.
我发誓我一定不会去你妈妈那里吃饭
I'm never going to your mama's house, I promise.
博比 鳄鱼肉是…
But Bobby, Bobby, 'gators are…
出了名的嫩
known to have the most succulent meat.
我理解
I understand.
请说英语好吗？
English, please. English.
我说过多少次了…
I mean, how many times have we…
我们不讲西班牙语 我告诉过你的
We don't speak Spanish. I told you that.
你们干嘛总要破坏…
Why you got to ruin it for me, man?
我自己的传统呢？
That's my heritage.
你随便说吧
Go with the Spanish. Whatever
你们还记得我们是怎么过周末的吗？
Hey, you guys remember weekends? Huh?
在芬维公园看红袜队的比赛
The Sox at Fenway.
- 美味的热狗和冰镇的啤酒 - 完美的一天
- Cold hotdog and a flat beer. - Perfect day
队长你呢？你也有完美的一天吗？
What about you, Captain? You got a perfect day?
我已经等不及去…
I just can't wait to hold…
第一次抱我的女儿
my baby girl for the first time.
- 好男人啊 - 这真是太…
- He's adorable. - That's too…
闭嘴！
Shut up!
我都准备好了
Hey, I'm ready to do this.
你们谁有胆量
Hey, any of y'all grow some balls,
就来操场上见我
come see me on the court, man.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
（卡塔尔特种作战司令部）
小心我的胯下运球
Watch this crossover, baby.
就像乔丹全盛时期一样
Like Jordan in his prime,
穿梭于锋线间
pushing through the front line.
- 让开点 小妞们 - 哦 伙计 搞什么？
- Step aside, ladies. - Oh, man. What?
- 伦诺克斯！- 你好啊
- Lennox! - Hey, what are you doing?
- 要水吗？- 谢谢
- Water? - Thank you
你要帮我拿装备吗？
Are you gonna help me with the gear?
夏普上校 有一身份不明的入侵者
Colonel Sharp, we have an inbound unidentified infiltrator,
距离10英里
10 miles out.
不明身份的飞机
Unidentified aircraft,
你现位于美军管制空域
you are in restricted US military airspace.
请表明身份并 向东飞行离开美军的领空
Squawk ident and proceed east out of the area.
猛禽1号 2号
Raptors one and two,
目标方向250 进行拦截
snap to heading two-five-zero to intercept.
目标距离10英里 没表明身份
Bogie is in the weeds ten miles out, not squawking.
不明身份的飞机
Unidentified aircraft,
我们会护送你到美军桑克森空军基地
we will escort you to US SOCCENT airbase.
如果你不遵从 我们会使用致命的武力
If you do not comply, we will use deadly force.
发现目标
Copy the bogie
机尾编号4500X
Tail 4500 X-ray.
长官 报告说4500X 在3个月前被击落了
Sir, says here 4500 X was shot down three months ago.
- 在阿富汗 - 这一定是一个错误
- Afghanistan. - That's got to be a mistake
- 检查 再检查 - 我检查过了 长官
- Check again, then recheck. - I did, sir.
我有一个朋友就在那架直升机上
A friend of mine was on that chopper.
不明身份的飞机
Unidentified aircraft,
我们会护送你到桑克森空军基地
we will escort you to US SOCCENT airbase.
雷达 飞行物在哪？
Radar, where's the inbound?
目标5英里 长官
Bogie's five miles out, sir.
- 我老婆在线吗？- 是的 队长
- My wife on? - Yes, Captain.
- 我的女士们 - 看
- My ladies! - Look.
哦 看啊 她都这么大了
Oh, my goodness. Look at her. She's getting so big.
看看她的小脸 真想去亲一口
Look at those cheeks. I just wanna chew on them.
我们的孩子真是漂亮
Baby, we made a good-looking kid.
我知道人们总是这么说
I know that people say that all the time,
我们生了一个漂亮的孩子 干得好
but, wow, we made one good-Iooking kid. Nice work.
她笑得真像你
She has your laugh
- 她笑了？- 第一次呢
- She laughed? - Her first one, yeah.
你确定她刚刚没有放屁吗？
You sure she didn't just fart?
没有 她可是个淑女
No, she's a lady.
她还不认识你 但是她会的
She doesn't know you yet, but she will.
4500X 好像有些不对劲
4500 X. Something's not right
目标着落了
Bogie's on the deck.
喔喔喔 雷达被干扰了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Radar's jammed.
直升机是干扰源
It's coming from the chopper
- 威尔？- 莎拉？
- Will? - Sarah?
莎拉 如果你能听见我
Hey, Sarah, if you can hear me,
我爱你 我很快就会回家
I love you and I'll be home soon.
- 到右边去 到右边去 - 检查弹药
- To the right. Go to the right. - Check fire
MH-53飞行员 关闭你的发动机
MH-53 pilot, power down now.
让你的机组人员下机 不然我们会杀了你们
Have your crew step out or we will kill you.
不要开火！待命！
Hold your fire! Stand by to engage!
上帝啊
My God.
他们炸了通讯天线 我们被攻击了
They bombed the antenna farm! We're under attack!
快走！快！
Go! Move! Move!
它是为了这些机密文件！
It's going after the files!
切断总电源！
Cut the hard lines!
我要钥匙 它被锁上了！
I need a key! It's locked!
快走！
Move! Move!
到这边！到这边！
Here, come here! Come here!
藏在这！
Here, hide in here!
哦 上帝啊
Oh, my God.
不！
No!
哦！
Oh!
怎么…
What the…
艾普斯 快走！
Epps, let's go!
（马歇尔高中）
维特维奇先生 该你了
Okay, Mr. Witwicky, you're up.
抱歉 我带了很多东西
Sorry, I got a lot of stuff.
瞧吧
Watch.
好的
Okay
对于我们家族…
For my family…
是谁干的？谁干的？同学们 要有责任感
Who did… Who did that? People! Responsibility.
好吧
Okay
对于家族史这个报告
So, for my family genealogy report,
我打算讲我的曾曾祖父
I decided to do it on my great-great-grandfather,
他是一个著名的人 阿奇伯尔德·维特维奇船长
who was a famous man, Captain Archibald Witwicky.
著名的探索家
Very famous explorer
实际上 他是第一个去探索…
In fact, he was one of the first to explore…
北极的人 那是一件非常困难的事
the Arctic Circle, which is a big deal.
在1897年
In 1897,
他带着41个勇敢的水手…
he took 41 brave sailors straight…
向北极出发
into the Arctic Shelf.
大家加把劲！快！举起来！
Move faster, men! Move! Chop! Heave!
冰结的比它化的还要快！
The ice is freezing faster than it's melting!
大家再加把劲！
Chop faster! Heave, men!
- 举起来！- 没有付出 就没有胜利
- Heave! - No sacrifice, no victory!
我们会到达那里的 伙计们！
We'll get to the Arctic Circle, lads!
这就是我要讲的故事
So that's the story, right?
我这里有一些基本资料
And here we have some of the basic instruments…
和工具 是19世纪水手所用的
and tools used by 19th-century seamen
这是四分仪
This here is the quadrant,
只要80美元就可以给你
which you can get for 80 bucks.
这些都是要卖的
It's all for sale, by the way.
这个六分仪
Like the sextant here.
50美元 非常超值
$50 for this, which is a bargain.
这个最酷了
These are pretty cool.
它是我曾曾祖父的眼镜
These are my grandfather's glasses.
我还没给它估价
I haven't quite gotten them appraised yet,
它见过很多有趣的事
but they've seen many cool things.
你还要卖了他的肝吗？
Are you going to sell me his liver?
维特维奇先生
Mr. Witwicky,
这不是跳蚤市场 这是11年级的课堂
this isn't show and sell. It's the 11th grade.
我想你的祖父不会
I don't think your grandfather would be
为你所作所为感到骄傲的
particularly proud of what you're doing
我知道 对不起 这只是…
I know. I'm sorry. I just, you know,
都是为了我的汽车基金
this is all going towards my car fund.
你可以告诉其他人 我在易趣卖
You can tell your folks. It's on eBay. I take PayPal.
接受贝宝和现金
Cold hard cash works, too.
指南针是一个很好的哥伦布节的礼物
And the compass makes a great gift for Columbus Day.
- 山姆 - 不好意思
- Sam! - Sorry.
不幸的是 我的曾曾祖父
Unfortunately, my great-great-grandfather,
虽然是个天才
the genius that he was,
却瞎了又疯了 被关进精神病院
wound up going blind and crazy in a psycho ward,
画这些奇怪的符号
drawing these strange symbols
说一些关于他所发现的
and babbling on about some giant ice man
巨大的冰人的事情
that he thought he'd discovered.
也许明天会有考试 也许不会
Okay. Might be a pop quiz tomorrow. Might not.
今晚在恐惧中入睡吧
Sleep in fear tonight.
要吗？50 40 30？
Here, you want? Here, 50. 40? 30?
- 山姆 - 对不起 对不起
- Sam? - Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
很不错 对吗？
Okay. Pretty good, right?
我想B-是一个不错的成绩
I'd say a solid B-.
给B-？
A B-?
你在我的课堂上说一些你曾曾祖父的无聊的事情
You were hawking your great-grandfather's crap in my classroom.
不 大家喜欢…
No, kids enjoy…
- 能帮个忙吗？- 干什么？
- Look, can you do me a favor? - What?
你能看一下窗外吗？
Can you look out the window for a second?
看到我父亲了吗？
You see my father?
- 坐在绿色的车里 - 嗯
- He's the guy in the green car. - Yeah.
我要告诉你一个梦想 一个男孩的梦想
Okay, I wanna tell you about a dream. A boy's dream.
一个男人答应那个男孩
And a man's promise to that boy
他看着我的眼睛说
He looked at me in the eye. He said,
儿子 我会给你买一辆车
"Son, I'm gonna buy you a car.
但是你需要给我2000美元和3个A
"But I want you to bring me $2, 000 and three As."
我已经有了2000美元和2个A
Okay? I got the 2, 000 and I got two As.
这是我的梦想 你的B-梦想破灭了
Okay? Here's the dream. Your B-. Dream gone. Kaput.
先生 你自问一下 如果是上帝 他会怎么做？
Sir, just ask yourself, what would Jesus do?
耶 太棒了！
Yes! Yes, yes.
怎么样？
So?
A- 但也算A
A-. It's an A, though.
等一等 我看不清楚 是A 没问题
Wait, wait, wait. I can't see. It's an A.
- 那么 通过啦？- 通过啦
- So I'm good? - You're good
我有一个惊喜给你 儿子
I got a little surprise for you, son.
什么样的惊喜？
What kind of…
小小的惊喜
Yeah, a little surprise.
不 不 不 不 爸爸！
No. No, no, no, no. Dad!
（保时捷车行）
- 你一定是在开玩笑 - 看？
- Oh, you got to be kidding me. - See?
是的 我是在开玩笑 你不会得到一辆保时捷
Yeah. I am. You're not getting a Porsche
你认为那很可笑吗？
You think that's funny?
是的 非常可笑
Yeah, I think it's funny.
- 你怎么回事？- 你真以为…
- What's wrong with you? - You think I'd really
我给你买的第一辆车就是保时捷？
get you a Porsche for your first car?
我以后不会再和你谈这件事了
I don't want to talk to you for the rest of this whole thing.
哦 拜托 就是个现实的玩笑
Oh, come on. It's just a practical joke.
一点不好笑
It's not a funny joke.
- 曼尼！- 怎么？
- Manny! - What?
别让你表弟穿这个
Get your cousin out of that damn clown suit.
他热得发晕了
He's having a heat stroke again.
吓坏了白人客户
Scaring white folks.
我很热！妆要化了 我眼睛疼
I'm hot! Makeup's melting. It hurts my eyes.
这？不！这是什么？
Here? No, no, no, what is this?
你…你说过半辆车
You said… You said half a car,
不是半辆破烂 爸爸
not half a piece of crap, Dad.
我像你这么大时
When I was your age,
能有辆车就很开心了
I'd have been happy with four wheels and an engine.
让我来解释解释 好吗？
Okay, let me explain something to you. Okay?
- 看没看过《40岁的处男》？- 看过
- You ever see 40-Year-Old Virgin? - Yeah.
好 这就是他
Okay, that's what this is.
这是50岁的处男
And this is 50-year-old virgin.
- 好吧 - 你想我以后变成这样吗？
- Okay. - You want me to live that life?
没有付出 就没有胜利
No sacrifice, no victory.
嗯 没有胜利 我知道
Yeah, no victory. You know, I got it.
- 我知道这句维奇家的格言 - 对
- The old Witwicky motto, Dad. - Right.
先生们
Gentlemen
鲍比·玻利维亚
Bobby Bolivia,
就像那个国家 除了不是逃来的
like the country, except without the runs.
想要点什么？
How can I help you?
我儿子要买他的第一辆车
Well, my son here, looking to buy his first car.
- 所以你来找我了？- 没办法
- You come to see me? - I had to.
那我们就是一家人了
That practically makes us family.
你可以叫我鲍比·B叔叔
Uncle Bobby B, baby. Uncle Bobby B.
- 山姆 - 山姆 我来跟你说
- Sam. - Sam, let me talk to you.
山姆 你的第一道大餐…
Sam, your first enchilada of freedom…
就在那里面
awaits underneath one of those hoods.
我来告诉你
Let me tell you something, son.
不是驾驶员挑车
A driver don't pick the car.
而是车挑驾驶员
The car'll pick the driver
这是人类和汽车间的缘分
It's a mystical bond between man and machine.
孩子 我本事很大的
Son, I'm a lot of things,
但不包括吹牛
but a liar's not one of them.
尤其不在我妈妈面前
Especially not in front of my mammy.
那就是我妈妈 嘿 妈咪！
That's my mammy. Hey, Mammy!
别那样
Don't be like that.
我要是有块石头 就砸你的头 婊子
If I had a rock, I'd bust your head, bitch.
我告诉你 伙计 她聋了
I tell you, man, she deaf, you know?
看这边
Well, over here,
每辆都不错 都是你所想要的
every piece of car a man might want or need.
这辆不错
This ain't bad
- 这车有赛车的条纹 - 是啊
- This one's got racing stripes. - Yeah.
有条纹…
It got racing…
这到底是哪辆？
Yeah, what's this? What the heck is this?
我不知道这辆车
I don't know nothing about this car
- 曼尼！- 干什么？
- Manny! - What?
这是谁的车？去查一下！
What is this? This car! Check it out!
我不知道 老板 我以前没见过！
I don't know, boss! I've never seen it! That's loco!
别唬我 曼尼 快去查查！
Don't go Ricky Ricardo on me, Manny! Find out!
感觉不错
Feels good.
- 多少钱 - 这个嘛…
- How much? - Well…
根据这辆车的外形
considering the semi-classic nature of the vehicle,
和特别的喷漆
with the slick wheels and the custom paint job…
漆已经掉色了
Yeah, but the paint's faded.
是的 但是喷漆是特殊的
Yeah, but it's custom.
那是特殊的掉色漆吗？
It's custom faded?
这是你第一辆车
Well, this is your first car.
我不指望你明白
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
5千
Five grand.
抱歉 不会超过4千
No, I'm not paying over four. Sorry.
孩子 从车里出来
Kid, come on, get out. Get out the car.
不 不 不 但是你说车挑驾驶员
No, no, no. You said cars pick their drivers.
但是 有时那个驾驶员…
Well, sometimes they pick a driver…
有一个抠门的父亲 快下车
with a cheap-ass father. Out the car.
这边这辆就4千美元了
Now, this one here for four Gs is a beaut.
那车也有赛车的条纹
There's a Fiesta with racing stripes over there
我不想要那个带条纹的福特嘉年华
No, I don't want a Fiesta with racing stripes.
这车有一个经典的引擎
This is a classic engine right here.
前几天卖一辆
I sold a car the other day…
哦 天啊
Gee. Holy cow.
- 不不不 别担心 - 你没事吧？
- No, no, no. No worries. - You all right?
我去弄个大锤把这个敲下来
I'll get a sledgehammer and knock this right out.
嘿 曼尼！
Hey, hey, Manny!
让你表弟弄些锤子来
Get your clown cousin and get some hammers
把这东西敲下去
and come bang this stuff out, baby!
…比人类伟大…
… greater than man…
那辆我最喜欢
That one's my favorite,
一路从阿拉巴马开过来
drove all the way from Alabammy.
4千
$4, 000.
（华盛顿特区）
史蒂文
Steve.
你好 部长先生
Hello, Mr. Secretary.
他们太年轻了
They're so young.
他们是最好的主题专家
They're the top subject matter experts, sir.
这些年国家安全局直接从高中招人
NSA's recruiting right out of high school these days.
同伴们 那是国防部部长
Guys, that's the Secretary of Defense.
我穿的衣服真不适合这个场合
I am so underdressed.
女士们 先生们 国防部部长
Ladies and gentlemen, the Secretary of Defense.
请坐
Please be seated.
我是约翰·凯勒
I'm John Keller.
你们应该想知道你们为什么会在这里
Obviously, you're wondering why you're here,
事实上是这样的
so these are the facts.
在昨天当地时间19时
At 1900 local time yesterday,
在卡塔尔的桑克森
the SOCCENT Forward Operations…
美军基地被攻击了
Base in Qatar was attacked.
具目前所了解的资料 没有幸存者
So far as we know, there were no survivors.
攻击的目的是为了…
The objective of the attack…
侵入军方的电脑网络
was to hack our military network
我们并不知道他们要找什么
We're not sure exactly what they're after,
但是我们知道…
but we do know…
他们的侵入被阻止了
that they were cut off during the assault,
所以我们认为…
which would lead us to assume…
他们会再次袭击
that they're going to try it again.
目前无人为攻击事件负责
Now, no one's taken responsibility for the attack.
我们现在唯一的线索…
And the only real lead we have so far…
是这个声音
is this sound.
那是侵入我们系统的信号
That's the signal that hacked our network.
国家安全局正在全力分析它
NSA's working at full capacity to analyze it,
希望来拦截未来的通讯
and intercept further communications,
我们需要你来找出谁是幕后的主脑
but we need your help to find out who did this.
你们都有很强的…
Now, you've all shown considerable ability…
信号分析技能
in the area of signals analysis.
现在情况紧急
We're on a hair-trigger here, people.
总统已经派出航母舰队
The President has dispatched battle groups
前往波斯湾和黄海
to the Arabian Gulf and Yellow Sea.
再也不会比这更严重了
This is as real as it's ever gonna get.
你们会由负责的官员领导
Now I'm gonna leave you to your officer-in-charge.
领队们会把你们分成小组…
You'll break up into teams…
开始工作
and you'll start your work.
祝我们好运
Good luck to us all.
好了 魔球 我有车了 我需要一个女朋友
All right, Mojo. I got the car. Now I need the girl.
我还需要钱带她出去玩
I need money to take out the girl is what I need
0个竞标
Zero bids
好极了 身无分文
Great. Broke
来吧 魔球 你想要止痛药吗？
Come on, Mojo. You want your pain pills?
还没熟透
No. Premature.
你好吗？
Good. What's up?
没什么 只是在开我的车
Nothing. You know, just driving my car.
开我的车
Driving my car.
就像是时钟发条
It's like clockwork.
我知道这东西让你恍惚了
All right, I know you get wasted on these things,
但你要是再在我床上撒尿
but if you piss in my bed again,
就到外面睡去 明白？
you're sleeping outside. Okay?
今天到此为止了 别吃了 瘾君子
That's it for today. No more. Crackhead.
- 荣恩 这里不平 - 是 也许吧
- Ron, this one is uneven. - Yeah. Probably.
这块要掉了
This one is wobbly
是的 我会解决它的
Yeah. I'll take care of that real soon.
我们能不能请一个专业的人？
Couldn't we have hired a professional?
- 哦 山姆… - 干什么？
- Oh, Sam… - What?
我不想在我的草坪上看到脚印
I do not like footprints on my grass.
什么…？没脚印啊
What foot… There's no footprints.
这就是我为什么修了入门径
That's why I built my path.
你为什么不从草地移到入门径上来？
So why don't you go from my grass onto my path, okay?
这草是属于整个家的
It's family grass, Dad.
当你拥有你自己的草地的时候
Well, when you own your own grass,
你会明白的
you'll understand.
这…我受不了了
This… I can't do it anymore
你把女性的饰品戴在一条雄性的狗身上
You're putting girl jewelry on a boy dog.
作为一条吉娃娃犬
He's got enough self-esteem…
他有严重的自信心问题
issues as a Chihuahua, Mom.
那是他的首饰
That's his bling.
在11点前回家！
I want you home at 11:00!
- 没问题 - 11点
- Yeah, all right. - 11:00!
看在上帝的份上 小心开车
Please, for the love of God, drive safely.
系上安全带！
Seat belt on!
喔 你可真小气
Wow. You are so cheap.
那是他的第一辆车 应该是这样的
Well, it's his first car. Supposed to be like that.
目前 我们无法确认
At this time, we can't confirm…
是否有幸存者存在
whether there were any survivors.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
我们现在进入防御状况四
Our bases worldwide are, as of now, at DEFCON Delta,
这是最高警戒
our highest readiness level.
我们面对着一个从未见过的
We're dealing with a very effective weapons system
非常强大的武器系统
that we have not come across before.
我们会为那些勇敢的士兵祈祷
But our prayers are with the families of the…
爸爸会没事的
Honey, Daddy's gonna be okay.
我以前从未见过这种武器系统
I've never seen a weapons system like this.
热成像显示…
The thermal shows this…
在它的外骨骼结构周围…
weird aura around the exoskeleton like it's…
有一个无形的能量罩
cloaked by some kind of invisible force field.
那不可能
That's impossible.
根本没有无形的能量罩
There's no such thing as invisible force fields.
除了在漫画里 对吗？
except in, like, comic book stuff, right?
- 我不明白 - 怎么了？
- Man, I don't know. - What is that?
我老妈 她有种天赋
My mama, she had the gift, you know?
她可以看到未来 我也有她的遗传
She saw things. I got the gene, too,
那个攻击我们的家伙
and that thing that attacked us?
我预感它还会再来
I got a feeling it ain't over.
你为什么不用你的巫术
How about you use those magic voodoo powers
让我们离开这里
and get us the hell out of here, huh?
当我照相的时候 我想它看到我了
When I took that picture, I think it saw me.
它盯着我看
It looked right at me.
我们要马上把它…
All right, we got to get this thing…
送到五角大楼
back to the Pentagon right away.
他们要知道我们的敌人是什么
They got to know what we're dealing with here.
无线电失灵了
My radio's fried.
天线没有信号
I got no communication with aerial.
马弗斯
Hey, Mahfouz.
你家离这里有多远？
How far do you live from here?
不远了 翻过那座山就到了
Not far. Just up that mountain.
- 那里有电话吗？- 是的
- Do they have a phone? - Yes.
好的 我们走
All right, let's hit it.
伙计 你确定我们被邀请了吗？
Dude, are you sure we're invited to this party?
当然了 迈尔斯 那是一个湖 是公共场所
Of course, Miles. It's a lake. Public property.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我的天啊 梅卡拉在这
Oh, my God, dude, Mikaela's here.
别做奇怪的事 好吧？
Just don't do anything weird, all right?
- 我看上不错 对不对？- 是的
- I'm good, right? - Yeah, you're good.
好的
Okay.
嘿 各位 快看
Hey, guys, check it out.
哦 嘿
Oh, hi.
嘿 伙计 你的车不错 嘿
Hey, bro. That car. It's nice. Hey.
你们来这里干什么？
So, what are you guys doing here?
我们来这里爬这棵树
We're here to climb this tree.
我看见了 很有趣
I see that. It looks… It looks fun.
- 嗯 - 我想我认识你
- Yeah. - You know, I thought I recognized you.
你去年参加过橄榄球队的预选 对吧？
You tried out for the football team last year, right?
回家找你妈妈吧
Let's go call your mom.
不 不 那是… 不是
Oh, no, no, that… No.
我并不是想参加预选
That wasn't like a real tryout.
我是在为写的书收集资料
I was researching a book I was writing.
- 哦 是吗？- 是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
哦？关于什么的？一塌糊涂的体育运动？
Yeah? What's it about? Sucking at sports?
不 那是关于…
No, it's about the link…
橄榄球和大脑受损的
between brain damage and football.
那是一本好书 你的朋友会喜欢它的
No, it's a good book. Your friends'll love it.
有上色的地方
You know, it's got mazes in it and,
立体折叠…
you know, little coloring areas,
还有图片 非常有趣
sections, pop-up pictures. It's a lot of fun.
真是好笑
That's funny.
算了 不要这样
Okay, okay. You know what? Stop.
我们去参加聚会吧
Hey, guys, I know of a party. Let's go, let's head.
快从树上下来…
You got to get out of the tree right now. Get…
快下来 拜托
Just get out of the tree right now, please.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
看到下来的动作了？
Did you see that dismount?
女孩们都在看我
All the chicks were watching.
你使我看起来像个傻瓜
You're making me look like an idiot.
我们刚才都像傻瓜
We both looked like idiots just now.
嘿 让我开怎么样？
Hey, how about you let me drive?
哦 不不不 这不是玩具车
Oh, no. No, no, no. This is not a toy.
这个22英寸的轮胎 我不想你开
These 22s, I don't want you grinding them. No.
为什么我可爱的小白兔…
Why doesn't my little bunny…
不跳到后座上去？
just hop in the back seat?
噢 天 我要告诉你
God, I can't even tell you how much…
我可不是你的小白兔
I'm not your little bunny.
好吧
Okay.
你会来找我的
You'll call me.
∮ 今晚谁开车送你回家？∮
∮ Who's gonna drive you home, tonight? ∮
嘿 伙计 你的收音机怎么了？
Hey, man, what's wrong with your radio?
- 今晚我要送她回家 - 什么？
- I'm gonna drive her home tonight. - What?
她可是个小骚货 伙计
She's an evil jock concubine, man.
让她去搭车吧
Let her hitchhike.
她家离这里有10英里远
She lives 10 miles from here, okay?
这是我唯一的机会
It's my only chance.
你要理解我 好吗？
You got to be understanding here, all right?
把她放在后座 我会安静的
All right. We'll put her in the back. I'll be quiet.
你是不是说“让她坐在后座”？
Did you say, "Put her in the back"?
我说坐前面
I called shotgun.
我不会让她坐后面
I'm not putting her in the back.
你得下车
You got to get out of my car.
- 这可违反了聚会规则 - 什么规则？
- That's a party foul. - What rules?
不能重色轻友
Bros before hos.
迈尔斯 我求你下车 好吗？
Miles, I'm begging you to get out of my car. Okay?
你不能这样对我
You can't do this to me.
你必须立即下车
You got to get out of my car right now.
∮ 你受伤时谁陪在你身边？∮
∮ Who's gonna come around when you break? ∮
梅卡拉 我是山姆
Mikaela! It's Sam.
维特维奇
Witwicky.
希望没有让你感到进退两难
I hope I didn't get you stranded or anything.
是吧？
You sure?
我可不可以把你带回家？
So listen, I was wondering if I could ride you home.
我是说我开车把你送回家
I mean give you a ride home in my car to your house.
上车吧
There you go.
那么…
So…
我真不敢相信我现在坐在这里
I can't believe that I'm here right now.
愿意的话你可以把头低下
You can duck down if you want.
我不会感到难过的
I mean, it won't hurt my feelings.
哦 不不不 我不是说和你在一块
Oh, no, no, no. I didn't mean… I didn't mean here with you.
我是说现在这种状况
I just meant here, like, in this situation,
我总是把自己至于这种境地
this same situation that I'm always in.
我不知道为什么
'Cause, I don't know,
我想 我是对肌肉男有特殊的喜好
I guess I just have a weakness for hot guys,
那种紧紧的肌肉 结实的臂膀
for tight abs and really big arms.
结实的臂膀？
Big arms?
这车上有几种新物件
Well, there's a couple new additions in the car.
我刚刚装了那个灯
Like, I just put in that light there.
还有这个迪斯可球
And that disco ball.
用那盏灯照这个迪斯可球
And so the light reflects off the disco ball.
没错
Yeah.
你是刚刚到这个学校的吗？
Are you… are you new to school this year?
这是你第一年在这里上学吗？
It's your first year here?
哦 不不
Oh, no, no.
我们从一年级开始就在同一所学校
We've been in the same school since first grade.
- 真的？- 没错
- Really? - Yeah.
真的是很久了
Yeah, a long time.
我们有同堂的课吗？
Well, do we have any classes together?
- 有的 - 真的？什么课？
- Yeah, yeah. - Really? Which?
历史 语言 数学 科学
History. Language arts. Math. Science.
- 你叫山姆 - 山姆 没错
- Sam. - Sam. Yeah.
- 山姆·维特齐齐 - 维特维奇
- Sam Wilkicky. - Witwicky.
天啊 我真是很对不起
God, you know what? I'm so sorry. I just…
- 没关系 - 我没认出你来
- No, it's cool. - I just didn't recognize you.
没什么 可以理解
Yeah, well, I mean, that's understandable.
不 不要 拜托
No, no, no. No. Come on.
抱歉 我才刚刚修过
Sorry, I'm just working out the kinks.
这是辆新车
You know, it's a new car.
∮ 当欲望来时 性爱疗法是我所需 ∮
∮ When I get that feeling I want sexual healing ∮
这收音机…你知道…
This radio is, like, you know…
也是个旧的 所以…
It's an old radio, too, so…
∮ 性爱疗法 ∮
∮ Sexual healing ∮
我也不知道为什么
Look, this isn't something that I, you know…
我没法关掉收音机
I can't get this radio to stop.
我不是故意的
Look, I wouldn't try this on you.
因为这有点浪漫…
'Cause this is like a romantic thing…
我不想这样的
that I'm not trying to do.
不应该对你…
Not that you're not worthy of…
这样做的
trying something like this on.
- 当然 - 我是你的朋友
- No, of course not. - I'm a friend of yours.
不是男女朋友 男女朋友之间才这样
I'm not a romantic friend. Romantic friends do this.
我是说 我不是那种朋友
I mean, I'm not that friend.
我是说 我们…我可以是的
I mean, we… I could be.
∮ 我感觉不错 ∮
∮ I feel good ∮
打开引擎罩
Just pop the hood.
白痴！闭嘴 闭嘴！
Stupid. Shut up, shut up, shut up.
哇哦 缸头真不错
Whoa, nice headers.
高置双泵渗碳缸头
You've got a high-rise double-pump carburetor.
真是印象深刻 山姆
That's pretty impressive, Sam.
双泵？
Double-pump?
汽油进的更快 你可以开的更快
It squirts the fuel in so you can go faster.
我喜欢开快一些
I like to go faster.
看起来你的…
And it looks like your…
配电盘封盖有些松了
distributor cap's a little loose.
是吗？你是怎么知道的？
Yeah? How'd you know that?
我爸爸 他是汽车机械师
My dad. He was a real grease monkey.
他教会我这些的
He taught me all about this.
我可以把它拆了
I could take it all apart,
清洗一下 再装起来
clean it, put it back together.
真奇怪 我一定不会花钱请你当修车工
That's weird.I just wouldn't peg you for mechanical.
噢 上帝啊
Oh, my God.
其实你也知道 我不声张
Well, you know, I don't really broadcast it.
男人不喜欢…
Guys don't like it when…
女人比他们更懂车
you know more about cars than they do.
特别是崔恩 他讨厌这些
Especially not Trent. He hates it.
不 我并不介意
Yeah, no, I'm cool with, you know,
女人来修引擎
females working on my engine.
实际上 我挺喜欢
I prefer it, actually.
好的 你想试一下点火吗？
Okay. You want to fire it up for me?
噢 对 没问题
Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.
- 谢谢 - 我在想
- Thanks. - You know, I was thinking.
如果崔恩是个混蛋
You know, if Trent's such a jerk,
你为什么还和他在一起？
why do you hang out with him?
嗯…我要走路回去了
You know what? I'm just… I'm gonna walk.
祝你的车好运
Good luck with your car.
好吧
All right.
走路有益健康 是吧
Walking's healthy, right?
哦 上帝 不 不 不
Oh, God, no, no, no, no, no, no.
拜托 快好起来吧
Come on, please. Please, you gotta work for me now.
不要让她走掉
Don't let her walk away.
拜托 拜托 求求你 求求你
Come on, come on, come on. Please, please.
∮ 宝贝回来吧 傻瓜都看得出来 ∮
∮ Baby come back any kind of fool could see ∮
嘿！
Hey!
∮ 都是为了你 ∮
∮ There was something in everything about you ∮
∮ 宝贝回来吧 你可以怪我的 ∮
∮ Baby come back you can blame it all on me ∮
嘿！
Hey!
等一下！
Wait a second!
∮ 我错了 我不能没有你 ∮
∮ I was wrong and I just can't live without you ∮
到了
There it is.
我今天很高兴 感谢你听我发牢骚
I had fun. So, you know, thanks for listening.
噢 嗯
Oh, yeah, yeah.
你…你是不是认为我很肤浅？
You… You think I'm shallow?
我觉得你…不 不 不
I think you're… No, no, no.
我觉得
I think…
你并非徒有其表
there's a lot more than meets the eye with you.
好的
Okay.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧 我们学校见
All right, I'll see you at school.
好的
All right.
真傻
That's stupid.
真傻的台词
That was a stupid line.
“你并非徒有其表” 真傻
"There's more than meets the eye with you." Stupid.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
哦 上帝 我喜欢这车
Oh, my God. I love my car.
（五角大楼 国家军事指挥中心）
嘿 伙计们 我想另一个小组找出原因了
Hey, guys, I think the other team figured it out.
伊朗人
Iran.
拜托 伙计
Come on, man.
这对伊朗科学家也太难了点
This is way too smart for Iranian scientists.
想想吧
Think about it.
你觉得呢？中国人？
What do you think, kid? Chinese?
不可能
No way.
这和中国所用的技术一点也不像
This is nothing like what the Chinese are using.
（空军一号）
这里是空军一号
This is Air Force One.
飞行高度330
Level of flight, level three-three-zero.
我们要找到这个敌人
We will hunt down this enemy. And when we do,
那时就能知道怎样对付他们
we'll know just what to do with them.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
（美军基地遭受重创）
很明显 幸存者很少
Apparently, there are very few survivors.
总统先生？
Yes, Mr. President?
给我拿一点点心来好吗？亲爱的
Yeah, can you wrangle me up some Ding Dongs, darling?
我加入空军一号就是给他拿点心的
I joined the Air Force to bring the man Ding Dongs.
我去储藏室
I'll be in storage.
该死的
Shoot.
真恶心
Gross.
你们听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
Are you getting this?
我想他们又在入侵军事网络了
I think they're hacking the network again.
（侦测到外来信号）
（搜索“冰人计划”）
（找到结果）
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
这个和卡塔尔的信号完全一致
This is a direct match to the signal in Qatar.
- 你在进行信号分析吗？- 应该吗？
- Are you running a diagnostic? - Should I be?
- 应该 - 我这就办
- Yes, you should. - So I am.
（开始上传文件）
（探测到病毒）
（无法识别文件上传中）
来人！它们正入侵空军一号的网络！
Someone! They're hacking into Air Force One!
我们需要一个高级分析师
We need a senior analyst.
- 我想它们植入了一个病毒 - 病毒？
- I think they're planting a virus. - A virus?
正在传输
It's streaming right now.
他们在植入病毒
They are planting a virus.
同时还从我们系统上…
and stealing a whole lot of data…
窃取了大量的信息
from your system at the same time.
红色警报 网络被入侵了
Code Red. We have a breach.
空军一号
Air Force One,
有人正在入侵军事网络
someone onboard has breached the military network.
货舱没有人
I'm in the cargo hold. Clear. Clear
- 你们必须切断热线 - 什么？
- You got to cut the hard lines. - What?
- 不管它们想要什么 它们正在得逞 - 长官？
- Whatever they want, they are getting it. - Sir?
请求切断防御网络
Permission to take down the Defense Network.
切断所有服务器的连接
Cut all server hard lines now.
（连接中断）
（北极探险家称发现冰人）
（发现者 维特维奇船长）
（终端停止）
有人动过这里的主机
Someone's tampered with the POTUS mainframe.
怎么…
What the…
底舱有人开枪 重复 有人开枪
Shots fired in the underdeck. Repeat, shots fired.
机组 准备紧急降落
Crew, prepare for emergency descent.
我要总统现在就进入地下掩体
I want our President in that bunker.
我要在他安全后
And I don't want to discuss a damn thing other…
再讨论现在这个问题
till that becomes reality.
这是我们的首要目标
That's our first priority.
也是我们现在的唯一目标
That's our only priority right now.
空军一号已经降落了
Air Force One is on the ground.
愚蠢的生物妄图朝我开枪
找到了火种源的线索
一个姓维特维奇的人看到过我们的文字
搜索维特维奇
必须找到万人迷217
哦 上帝 不 不 不！
Oh, God. No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
那是我的车！
That's my car!
不！
No!
不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
爸爸 报警
Dad, call the cops!
你要开我的车去哪？
Where you going with my car, buddy? Where you going?
我要报警 我的车被偷了！
Hello? 911 emergency! My car has been stolen!
我正在追他
I'm in pursuit! Right?
所有单位和中队都要行动！
I need all units, the whole squadron.
把所有人都叫来！
Bring everyone!
不！别问为什么 行吗？
No, don't ask me questions, all right?
我爸爸是邻居保安计划主管！
My father's the head of the neighborhood watch!
哦 上帝
Oh, my God.
我叫山姆·维特维奇
My name is Sam Witwicky.
不论谁看到这个 我的车活了
Whoever finds this, my car is alive, okay?
看到了？
You saw that?
这是我的遗言
Since this is my last words on Earth,
我爱你爸爸 妈妈
I just wanna say, Mom, Dad, I love you,
如果你们从床下找到色情书刊
and if you find Busty Beauties under my bed,
那不是我的
it wasn't mine.
我是替迈尔斯在保存 不 等等…
I'm holding it for Miles. No, no, wait that…
好吧 那不是真的
Okay, that's not true.
查尔叔叔给我的 对不起
It's mine and Uncle Charles gave it to me. I'm sorry.
魔球 我爱你
Mojo, I love you.
（内有恶犬）
不！不！不！不！
No! No! No! No!
哦 上帝
Oh, my God.
不 你是好狗 好狗 好狗！
No, you're a good dog! Good dog! Good dog!
哦 上帝
Oh, my God.
喔 嘿嘿嘿 喔 好吧！哦 哦
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey! Whoa! All right! Oh! oh! oh!
好吧 求求你 别杀我！
Okay. Please, please don't kill me!
对不起 钥匙给你了 我不要了！
I'm sorry! Take the keys! I don't want them!
车是你的了！
Car's yours!
听着 听着 听着
Listen, listen, listen.
- 真好 你们来了 - 把手举起来！
- Good, you're here. - Let me see your hands!
- 不不不 不是我 - 把手举起来让我看到
- No, no, no! It's not me! - Let me see your hands.
那个人在里面
The guy's inside.
住嘴 走向警车
Shut up! Walk towards the car.
把头顶到引擎罩上
Put your head on the hood.
他们终于还是侵入了…
Whoever did this finally managed…
我们的防卫网
to infiltrate our defense network,
他们当时尝试侵入我们的卡塔尔基地
which is what they tried to do in Qatar,
不过这次他们得逞了
only this time it worked.
- 他们都弄到了什么？- 目前还未知
- What did they get? - We still don't know.
告诉我病毒的情况
Talk to me about the virus.
是一种蜘蛛型病毒
It's a Spider-bot virus.
我们还不了解它的作用
We're not sure what it's going to do,
不过有可能会侵害我们的系统
but it may cripple the system.
- 我们能阻止它吗？- 每一次我们想消灭它
- Can we stop it? - Every time we try an antivirus,
它会变种而躲过
it adapts and speeds up.
好像不单纯是一种病毒了
It's like it's not a virus anymore.
变成了系统
It's become the system.
很明显 这是大规模…
Obviously the first phase of…
反美攻击的第一阶段
a major attack against the US.
有此能力的国家包括
The only countries with this kind of capability
俄罗斯 北朝鲜 也许还有中国
are Russia, North Korea, maybe China.
抱歉 我想事情不是这样的
I'm sorry, that's not correct.
对不起 女士
Excuse me, young lady.
我没留意你在场 你是…？
I didn't see you standing there. You would be who?
是我侦测到他们的攻击
I'm just the analyst who detected the hack.
等一下 是你？你侦测到的？
Hold on. It was you? You did it?
- 她的团队 - 长官 我只是想说明
- Her team. - Sir, I was just trying to say,
他们在10秒之内就攻破了我们的防火墙
they hacked your firewall in 10 seconds.
就算是最尖端最具攻击性的计算机
Okay. Even a supercomputer with a brute force attack
也需要至少二十年的时间才能做到
would take 20 years to do that.
那么我想…
Maybe you can explain, then,
请你给我解释
how our latest satellite imagery…
北朝鲜加倍了他们的国防？
shows North Korea doubling its naval activity?
也许这只是他们的防护措施？
Maybe it's a precaution,
我们不是也一样？
because isn't that what we're doing?
信号图像正在不断发展
The signal pattern is learning.
他们具有自发进化的能力
It's evolving on its own.
这不是线性变换所能解释的了
And you need to move past Fourier transfers
已经提升到量子力学的范畴
and start considering quantum mechanics.
在这个地球上并不存在如此复杂的东西
There is nothing on Earth that complex.
那么有机体呢？具有生命能力的有机体
What about an organism? A living organism?
例如DNA构成的计算机？
Maybe some kind of DNA-based computer?
我知道这个听起来是天方夜谭…
And I know that that sounds crazy…
够了 够了
That's enough. That's enough.
我们拥有六层楼的同仁
We have six floors of…
在协力分析调查这个
analysts working on this thing.
如果你能找到证据来支持你的观点
Now, if you can find proof to back up your theory,
我乐意听取你的意见
I'm gonna be happy to listen to you.
但如果你继续在这里信口开河
But if you don't get a filter on that brain-mouth thing,
就请你走人 听清楚了？
you're gonna be off the team. You understand?
（警察局）
听着 我当时非常清醒
Look, I can't be any clearer
简直“至清无鱼”
than how crystal clear I am being.
- 他就那么站起来了 - 站了起来
- It just stood up. - It just stood up.
哇…好恐怖哦
Wow. That's really neat.
好吧 这个拿去
Okay, chiefie.
把这个灌满 别滴的到处都是
Time to fill her up. And no drippy-drippy.
你嗑的什么药？
What are you rolling?
笑气？
Whippets?
巴比妥？还是少许大麻？
Goofballs? A little wowie sauce with the boys?
- 不 我没有嗑药 - 这是什么？
- No, I'm not on any drugs. - What's these?
你口袋里找到的“魔球”
Found it in your pocket."Mojo."
你们小孩现在流行吃这个？
Is that what the kids are doing now?
来点“魔球”？
Little bit of Mojo?
那是我狗狗的止痛药
Those are my dog's pain pills.
你知道…吉娃娃…
You know, a Chihuahua. A little…
怎么回事？
What was that?
你在盯着我的枪 想当“50分”？
You eyeballing my piece, 50 Cent?
想试试？那你就动一下试试！
You wanna go? Make something happen. Do it.
不过我告诉你 我一定会让你开花
'Cause I promise you I will bust you up.
你是不是嗑药了？
Are you on drugs?
（中东 卡塔尔）
但愿这条电话线还管用
Let's hope this telephone line works.
嘿 抬头！
Hey, heads up!
抬头！嘿！抬头！
Heads up! Hey! Heads up!
怎么回事？
What the heck was that?
说英语啊 老弟
English, dude. English.
喔！
Whoa!
当心！
Watch out!
- 开火！- 靠近了！靠近了！
- Open fire! - Contact! Contact!
大家安静
Everybody, quiet. Settle.
哦 妈呀 什么玩意？
Whoa, mother… What the hell is…
快起来 快跑！
Get up! Get up! Come on!
跑 快跑！
Go! Move it!
找掩护！
Take cover!
菲格 保护后面！
Fig! Cover the rear!
开火！快！菲格 保护后面！
Cover fire! Move it! Fig, cover the rear!
艾普斯 保护后面！
Epps! Cover the rear! Move it!
快！给我把机枪！
Come on! Give me a mag!
你爸爸呢？你爸爸呢？
Where's your papa? Where's your papa?
爸爸！
Papa!
先生 我们需要电话
Sir, we need… I need a telephone.
- 电话 电话 对！- 电话！
- Telephone, telephone, yes! - Telephone!
嘿 我给我把机枪！
Hey, I need a mag! Give me a mag!
- 手机！- 真谢谢你
- Cell phone! - I don't know how to thank you
开火！
Fire!
帮我接五角大楼 紧急电话！
This is an emergency Pentagon call!
我要你…听到吗？
I need you to… Do you understand?
这是紧急…
It's an emergency Pentagon…
我没有信用卡！
I don't have a credit card!
先生 你的态度根本…
Sir, the attitude is not going to…
无法提高办事效率
speed things up any bit at all.
请你对着话筒…
I'm going to ask you to speak…
把话说清楚
into the mouthpiece very clearly.
我正在打仗！
I'm in the middle of a war!
这真他妈荒唐！
This is frigging ridiculous!
弹药！
Ammo!
我需要张信用卡！
I need a credit card!
- 艾普斯！你的钱包呢？- 口袋里
- Epps! Where's your wallet? - Pocket!
- 哪个口袋？- 屁股口袋里！
- Which pocket? - My back pocket!
你有那么多屁股口袋！
You got 10 back pockets!
左边屁股！左边屁股！
Left cheek! Left cheek! Left cheek!
好的 继续射击！
All right, keep shooting! Keep shooting!
好 有VISA卡
Okay, it's Visa.
还有 先生 您听说过
Also, sir, have you heard about
我们的“至尊全球服务”超值套餐吗？
our premium plus world-service gold package?
不 我不要什么超值套餐！
No, I don't want a premium package!
艾普斯！五角大楼！
Epps! Pentagon!
报告情况
Give me a status.
长官 我们追踪到一支
Sir, we're tracking a…
在卡塔尔遭受攻击的特种部队
Special Ops team under fire in Qatar.
他们说是基地袭击的幸存者
They say they're survivors of the base attack.
幸存者？
Survivors?
我这辈子还没见过这东西！
I ain't never seen this in my life!
需要武装直升机立即支援！
Need gunships on station ASAP!
掠食者马上赶到
Predator's coming up in a minute.
我们正联系最近的空中预警机
We're linking the call to the nearest AWACS.
不知道 伙计 我不…伙计
Unknown, man. I don't… man.
如果你看到这玩意儿…
If you seen this shit…
掠食者预计两分钟后到达
Predator ETA two minutes.
嘿！让开！
Hey! Make way!
- 这是什么？- 我不知道
- What is that? - I don't know.
我们现在就需要空中支援
We need air support and we need it now.
对不明物体进行密集型致命打击
Roll in strike package Bravo on unknown target.
敌我鉴别代码TW0300Z
I authenticate Tango Whiskey at time 0300 Zulu.
所有空军注意
Attention, all aircraft.
这将是次危险的近距离攻击任务
This will be a danger close-fire mission.
武器 我刚刚接到猎鹰特种队的电话
Weapons, I just got a call from Falcon Ops.
谁离目的地比较近？
Who's closer to Kill Box One Alpha?
- 贪婪者 长官 - 好的
- Send the Hogs, sir. - Okay, send the Hogs over…
派贪婪者去 这是次危险的…
to Kill Box One Alpha. It's a danger close…
派贪婪者前往目的地
Switch the Hogs to Kill Box One Alpha,
高度300英尺
300 feet danger close.
目标在地面
Friendlies in the area.
南部的橘色烟标识的是我们的7人小队！
Seven-man team north of orange smoke!
到达指定区域 可以攻击
Received Kill Box One Alpha. Engage hostile.
攻击西面 目标明显！
Attack direction west! You're clear and hot!
攻击 报告贪婪者的情况
Strike, tell me status of Hog right now.
贪婪者一号 暗星一号 报告情况
Hog One-One Dark Star status.
- 伦诺克斯！破甲弹来了！- 快引导目标！
- Lennox! The heat's coming! - Laze the target!
我们发射了激光制导导弹！引导目标！
We got a beam-rider incoming! Laze target!
- 准备！破甲弹来了！- 什么？引导它啊！
- Ready! Heat's coming! - What? Bring it!
在目标附近受到雷达干扰
Receiving radar jamming in vicinity of target.
他妈没办法干掉那东西了
No frigging way that thing's still not down
幽灵32号 使用105毫米弹 密集攻击
Spooky Three Two, use 105 shells. Bring the rain.
地面部队请求…
Be advised, ground team…
使用105火炮
is requesting 105 sabot rounds.
干掉了吗？
Did we lose them?
疣猪1号确认目标被消灭
Warthog One confirm visual on friendlies.
菲格在哪？
Where's Fig?
- 菲格！菲格！- 啊 上帝！
- Fig? Fig? - Oh, God!
- 该死的！- 找医生来！
- God damn it! - Get a medic!
找医生来！
Get a medic!
- 对不起 - 黑鹰…
- I'm sorry. - Black Hawk…
医生来了 坚持住 他脉搏微弱
We'll get a medic. Just hold on. He's got a pulse
我们需要救伤直升机 一人重伤
We need a medevac. One man down.
需要立即治疗
Patient care category urgent
带他们回家
Bring them home.
立即带他们回本土
You get those men stateside right now.
让他们在10小时之内向我汇报
I want them debriefed in 10 hours.
这世上只有一个黑客…
There's only one hacker in the world…
能破解这代码
who can break this code.
嘿！等等！停下来！
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Wait! Stop!
很抱歉打搅你
I am sorry to bother you.
- 玛吉？- 听着 我需要你的帮助
- Maggie? - Listen, I need your help.
不 这是我的私人场所
No! This is my private area,
我的禅静之所
my place of Zen and peace.
- 听我说 - 格伦 是谁啊？
- Listen to me. - Glen! Who is it?
闭嘴 奶奶！
Shut up, Grandma!
你来这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
帮我个忙 好吗 拜托？
Just give me a break, will you, please?
奶奶！喝你的果汁去吧！
Grandmama! Drink your prune juice!
- 打到几级了 伙计？- 六级
- What level are you on, man? - Six.
喔 老大来了
Oh, here come the matrix! Here come the matrix!
格伦 说真的
Glen, seriously,
你不是想看“机密”吗？
don't you want to see something classified?
耶 低点
Yeah. Get low.
很好 很好 双击
Here we go. Here we go. Double tap.
嘿 我暂停了
Hey, I just paused it. I just paused it.
嘿 给我几分钟
Hey. I need a moment.
- 拜托 - 对不起
- Please. - Sorry.
嘿 伙计 帮我存档
Hey, man, save my game.
有多机密？
How classified?
是那种我要是给你看
Like "I will go to jail for the rest…
下半辈子就要在牢里过的机密
"of my life for showing you" classified.
耶！就看一眼！
Yes! One quick peek.
袭击我们卡塔尔基地的怪物
Special Ops got a thermal snapshot…
被我们的特种部队拍了照
of whatever hit the base in Qatar.
我想看看
I want to see it.
相机已经被毁坏了 长官
Well, the imager was damaged, sir.
工作人员正在尝试修复相机
The rangers are en route with the imager,
但我们现在还有个安全隐患
but we also have a security issue.
记录显示某个分析师
Circle logs indicate one of the analysts…
拷贝了入侵信号
made a copy of the network intrusion signal.
信号能量真是太高了
The signal strength is through the roof.
你说你是从哪弄到的？
Where did you say you got this?
他在不到一分钟的时间
It hacked the national military…
入侵国家军事安全防卫系统
air-guard frequency in less than a minute.
- 不可能 - 是的
- No way. - Yeah.
看上去在这信号中还暗藏着信息
Looks like there's a message embedded in the signal.
我终于可以大显身手了
Let me work my magic.
“冰人计划”？
"Project Iceman"?
- 什么是第七区组织？- 维特维奇船长又是谁？
- What's Sector Seven? - Who is Captain Witwicky?
你又在玩游戏了？
Are you playing those video games again?
警察！警察！
Cops! Cops!
FBI！让开！
FBI! Clear right!
把他抓住！把他抓住！
Lock it down! Lock it down!
警察！
Cops!
我什么都不知道
I don't know.
等等！我是无辜的！我是…
Wait! I'm just a cousin! I'm just a…
别踩我奶奶的地毯！
Get off my Grandmama's carpet!
她不喜欢人踩她的地毯！
She don't like nobody on the carpet!
尤其是警察！
Especially police!
一个小时之前有超过40架C-17
It was an awesome spectacle here an hour ago
运输机由此基地升空 场面颇为壮观
when over 40 C-17 s lifted off of this very base.
目的地尚未获知
We're not told where they're going.
- 政府方面对于发生的情况… - 早上好 小魔
- The government has been very quiet about… - Morning, Mo.
也是三缄其口
what's going on…
- 魔球 魔球 - 但他们直接朝着
- Mojo. Mojo. - But in our, they were headed directly
北韩方向前进
towards North Korea.
别这么早就开始叫唤 好吗 魔球？
Stop with the barking, Mojo. It's too early. Please?
迈尔斯 迈尔斯 听着
Miles? Miles, listen to me. Listen.
我的车 它自己跑了
My car, it stole itself, okay?
你在胡说些什么呢 伙计？
What are you talking about, man?
在我家院子里 那辆着魔的车追着我不放
Satan's Camaro. In my yard. It's stalking me.
停下！
Stop!
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
啊 我的天！
Oh, my God!
山姆？
Sam?
嗨
Hi.
你这个…很有型啊
That was… That was really awesome.
- 噢 是很有型 - 你没事吧？
- Well, it felt awesome. - Are you okay?
我不太好
I'm not okay, all right?
我快要抓狂了
I'm losing my mind a little bit.
我正被我的车追呢 我得跑路了
I'm getting chased by my car right now. I got to go.
我一会儿再去找你们
You know what?I'm gonna catch up with you guys later.
哦 太好了 警察
Oh, great. Cops.
（行暴欺良）
长官！
Officer!
听我说！
Listen!
啊 真疼
Oh, that hurt.
听我说！
Listen to me!
感谢上帝 你在这里！我从没这么惨过！
Thank God you're here! I've had the worst day ever!
我骑着我妈的自行车
I've been… I've been followed here…
被一路追踪到这里
on my mother's bike! Right?
我的车就在那儿
And my car's right there…
它一路追着我到这里！
and it's been following me here!
下车啊！
So get out of the car!
不！停下！啊 上帝 好吧 好吧 够了！
No! Stop! Oh, God. Okay, okay! Okay, all right!
够了！对不起！我…
Okay! I'm sorry! I'm…
我没想碰你的车！
I didn't mean to hit your car! Look!
好的 听着 停下 停下！
Okay, look, look, look! Stop, stop!
求你了 你想要什么？
Please! Okay, what do you want from me?
好的
Okay.
啊 上帝 不 不！
Oh, God, no! No!
啊 该死 啊 该死！上帝 该死！
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, shit, shit! Oh, God! Oh, shit!
真是噩梦！
It's a bad dream.
你的用户名是不是“万人迷先生217”？
Are you username LadiesMan217?
你在说什么？
I don't know what you're talking about!
你的用户名是不是“万人迷先生217”？
Are you username LadiesMan217?
是啊
Yeah.
你在易趣的拍卖物品21153在哪？
Where is eBay item 21153?
眼镜在哪？
Where are the glasses?
退后！
Get back!
停车！
Stop!
上帝！
God!
你怎么了 山姆？
What is your problem, Sam?
那里有个怪物
Okay, there's a monster right there!
刚刚袭击了我！
It just attacked me!
又来了！
Here he comes!
快起来 起来快跑
All right, get up. Get up and run!
你快跑
You have to run! Okay.
山姆 那个是什么？
Sam, what is that thing?
你快上车 上车
You have to get in the car. Get in.
我可不想
I don't want to.
- 上车 相信我 相信我！- 山姆
- Get in the car. Trust me. Trust me! - Sam
上车 快 快 快！
Get in! Go, go, go, go, go.
快 快 快！
Go, go, go, go!
啊 上帝 我们要死了 我们要死了！
Oh, God! We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
不 不会的 我们不会死
No, we're not. No, we're not gonna die.
- 啊 上帝！- 相信我 他很厉害！
- Oh, my God! - Trust me. He's a kick-ass driver!
啊 我的天 不！
Oh, my God! No!
我们要死了！
We're gonna die!
啊 我的天！
Oh, my God!
我们被锁在里面了
We're locked in.
车也无法发动
The car won't start.
至少我们躲开了怪物 对吧？
At least we ditched the monster, right?
好的
Okay.
时机到了
Time to start.
他要抓住我了 天啊
He's got me! Oh, God!
他会杀了我的！
He's going to kill me!
不 不 不！
No. No, no, no!
下来！
Get off!
杀了它！杀了它！
Kill it! Kill it!
抓住它 抓住它 抓住它
Get it, get it, get it, get it!
没了头就不行了吧？
Not so tough without a head, are you?
来 过来
Here, come on.
这是什么？
What is it?
是机器人
It's a robot.
但是像…
But like a…
是另一种…
Like a different…
超级先进的机器人
You know, like a super-advanced robot.
大概是日本机器人
It's probably Japanese.
对 肯定是日本的
Yeah, it's definitely Japanese.
你现在怎么办？
What are you doing?
我想他不会伤害我们
I don't think it wants to hurt us.
他要是想的话 一定一早就动手了
It would have done that already.
真的吗？你会讲机器人语吗？
Really? Well, do you speak robot?
因为他们俩刚刚…
Because they just had,
进行了一场生死决斗
like, a giant droid death match.
我觉得我有他要的东西
I think it wants something from me.
什么？
What?
因为另外一个…
Well, 'cause the other one…
跟我提过我的易趣网页
was talking about my eBay page.
你真是我见过的最无厘头的人
You are the strangest boy I have ever met.
- 你会说话吗？- 卫星收音机
- Can you talk? - XM Satellite Radio…
数字广播系统…
Digital cable brings you…
哥伦比亚广播系统…
Columbia Broadcasting System…
你是通过广播讲话？
So you… You talk through the radio?
谢谢你 你很漂亮
Thank you, you're beautiful.
你太棒了 太棒了
You're wonderful, you're wonderful.
那…昨晚是怎么回事？那是什么？
So, what was that last night? What was that?
来自浩渺宇宙的…
Message from Starfleet, Captain…
星河舰队长官的讯息…
Throughout the inanimate vastness of space…
太空访客会如天使般成群降临
Angels will rain down like visitors from heaven!
哈利路亚！
Hallelujah!
太空访客？什么…
Visitors from heaven? What…
你是什么 是外星人还是…？
What are you, like, an alien or something?
还有别的问题吗？
Any more questions you want to ask?
他要我们上车
He wants us to get in the car.
可是去哪儿呢？
And go where?
50年之后
Fifty years from now,
当你回望今生
when you're looking back at your life,
你想后悔当初…
don't you want to be able to say…
没胆上这辆车吗？
you had the guts to get in the car?
这车是个不错的司机呢
This car's a pretty good driver.
我知道
I know.
你为什么不坐在驾驶位上？
Why don't you go sit in that seat, there?
我才不要坐那 他在开呢
I'm not going to sit in that seat. He's driving.
嗯
Yeah.
你说得对
You're right.
- 要么你坐在我膝盖上？- 为什么？
- Well, maybe you should sit in my lap. - Why?
这里只有一个安全带
Well, I have the only seat belt here.
安全第一嘛
You know, safety first.
- 嗯 好吧 - 行吗？
- Yeah, all right. - Right?
- 当然 - 好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
看 好多了吧
There, see? That's better.
- 好的 - 好的
- Okay. - Okay
你这个“安全带”之计
You know, that seat belt thing…
还使得蛮圆滑嘛
was a pretty smooth move.
谢谢
Thank you.
其实我想不通
You know what I don't understand?
他既然这么厉害
Why, if he's supposed to be,
是个超级先进的机器人
like, this super-advanced robot,
为什么还要变回…
does he transform back into…
这么一坨烂车？
this piece-of-crap Camaro?
哇！哇！
Whoa! Whoa!
你看 这样不行 看见没？
Oh, see? No. Get… No, that doesn't work. See?
开走！你个混蛋！
Move it, you moron!
这下好了…看见没？
Great, now… See?
太妙了
Fantastic.
你把他气跑了
Now you pissed him off.
这个车很敏感的
That car is sensitive.
我的4000美金就这么跑了
I mean, $4000 just drove off.
什么？
What?
这是你…
This is you…
啊 我的天！
Oh, my God!
（我的乳牙）
上来 我们走
Come on, let's go.
这是我见过最酷的事情
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen!
到处都在爆炸！
Explosions everywhere!
比《绝世天劫》还要劲爆…
This is easily a hundred times cooler…
一百倍！我对天发誓！
than Armageddon. I swear to God!
着火了 着火了！
Fire, fire, fire, fire!
啊 天！
Whoa! Sweet!
啊 伙计 我希望这家伙交了陨石险
Oh, dude, I hope this guy's got asteroid insurance,
因为他太惨了！
'cause he is so boned!
那是什么？
What is that?
树上有东西 伙计
There's something in the tree, dude.
不 树旁有什么东西！
No, there's something in the thing by the tree!
你们能给我一块陨石吗？
Could you guys just give me a space rock?
对不起 请问你是不是牙仙？
Excuse me, are you the tooth fairy?
嘿 宝贝
Hey, sweetheart,
你怎么一个人在这儿！
what are you doing out here by yourself?
我的天哪！游泳池怎么了！
Holy God! What happened to the pool?
你是不是山姆·詹姆斯·维特维奇
Are you Samuel James Witwicky,
阿切邦·维特维奇的后代？
descendent of Archibald Witwicky?
他们知道你的名字
They know your name.
嗯
Yeah.
我叫擎天柱
My name is Optimus Prime.
我们是来自…
We are autonomous robotic…
塞伯坦星球的机械生命体
organisms from the planet Cybertron.
也可以简称为汽车人
But you can call us Autobots for short.
汽车人
Autobots.
什么是“超辣的辣妹”？
What's cracking, little bitches?
这是我的副手 爵士
My first lieutenant. Designation, Jazz.
看来这地方挺有型
This looks like a cool place to kick it.
你哪里学来的这种调子？
What is that? How did he learn to talk like that?
我们从互联网上…
We've learned Earth's languages…
学到地球人的语言
through the World Wide Web.
这是我的武器专家 铁皮
My weapons specialist, Ironhide.
- 今天你感到好运降身吗 小子？- 别吓人了 铁皮
- You feeling lucky, punk? - Easy, Ironhide.
开玩笑啦 只是想给他秀一下我的大炮
Just kidding. I just wanted to show him my cannons.
我们的医学专家 救护车
Our medical officer, Ratchet.
你身上的激素水平
The boy's pheromone level suggests…
显示你想跟这位女士亲热
he wants to mate with the female.
这位是你的守护者 你已经认识了 大黄蜂
You already know your guardian, Bumblebee.
大黄蜂 对吧？
Bumblebee, right?
检测系统 嗯 挺好的
Check on the rep Yep, second to none.
你就是我的守护者 哈？
So you're my guardian, huh?
他的发声系统在战斗受到破坏
His vocal processors were damaged in battle.
我在想办法把他治好
I'm still working on them.
你们为什么在这里？
Why are you here?
我们是来找火种源的
We are here looking for the All Spark.
而且一定要抢在威震天前面
And we must find it before Megatron.
威什么？
Mega-what?
我们的星球曾是一个强大的帝国
Our planet was once a powerful empire,
平静祥和
peaceful and just,
直到有一天 威震天出卖了我们
until we were betrayed by Megatron,
他是霸天虎的首领
leader of the Decepticons.
不服从他们的势力都被消灭
All who defied them were destroyed.
而我们的星球也在战争中消逝殆尽
Our war finally consumed the planet,
火种源也消失在星际之间
and the All Spark was lost to the stars.
威震天尾随它来到地球
Megatron followed it to Earth,
正是在那里维特维奇船长发现了他
where Captain Witwicky found him.
我的祖父
My grandfather.
那是一个意外 却把我们的命运纠缠在一起
It was an accident that intertwined our fates.
回来！
Come back!
它好像找到了什么
I think the dogs have found something.
冰面开裂了！
The ice is cracking!
船长！抓住绳子 船长！
Captain! Grab my rope, Captain!
我没事 伙计们！
I'm all right, lads!
要给你扔条绳子吗 船长？
Can we throw you a rope, Captain?
威震天在拿到能量体之前
Megatron crash-landed…
坠落到地球上了
before he could retrieve the Cube.
伙计们！我们有个重大发现！
Men! We've made a discovery!
他无意中启动了它的导航系统
He accidentally activated his navigation system.
能量体在地球上的座标
The coordinates to the Cube's location on Earth
由此印在了他的镜片上
were imprinted on his glasses.
你怎么知道眼镜的？
How'd you know about his glasses?
- 易趣网 - 易趣网
- eBay. - eBay
如果霸天虎们找到了火种源
If the Decepticons find the All Spark,
他们就会用它的能量转换…
they will use its power to transform…
地球上的机器 建立新的军队
Earth's machines and build a new army.
届时人类便会灭亡
And the human race will be extinguished.
山姆·维特维奇 地球的存亡就掌握在你的手上了
Sam Witwicky, you hold the key to Earth's survival.
眼镜还在你那儿吧？
Please tell me that you have those glasses.
（大西洋上空某处）
这简直就是个能自我修复的装甲
It's like a self-regenerating molecular armor.
看看脱壳穿甲弹打的弹孔
Look at the scorch mark where the sabot round hit.
直穿而过
Melted right through.
穿甲弹是不是可以…
Hey, aren't sabots hot-Ioaded for,
产生6000度的高温
like, a 6, 000-degree magnesium burn?
很接近 能烧熔坦克装甲
Close to it. It melts tank armor.
因此它的金属表面一定会在极高温下有反应
So this metal skin must react to extreme heat.
- 注意！- 啊！
- Heads up! - Oh!
你不是说这鬼东西已经死了吗？
I thought you said that thing was dead, man!
捆住它！捆住！这东西很邪门！
Strap it down! Strap it! This thing is wicked.
好的 联系北方司令部
All right, get on the horn with Northern Command.
告诉他们我们的有效武器…
Tell them that our effective weapon…
是高温穿甲弹
is high-heat sabot rounds.
建议所有的直升机都配备这种弹药 去吧！
Recommend we load them on all the gunships. Go.
这块你要不要？
You want that piece?
玛吉 你听我说
Okay, Maggie, look.
我告诉你接下来会怎样
Let me break it down to you how it's gonna happen.
等下进来的人
They gonna come through that door…
肯定有唱黑脸 有唱白脸
and be good cop, bad cop.
别中圈套 好吗？
Don't fall for that, all right?
所以我才吃这些东西
That's why I ate their food.
看吧 他们把吃的放这儿
See, they put the plate of…
是要试探你是不是心虚
donuts out here to test your guilt.
如果你不吃 就说明你心虚
If you don't touch it, you're guilty.
所以我整盘都吃啦 整盘！
I ate the whole plate. The whole plate. Okay?
就咱俩
It's me and you.
他们进来时 你什么也别说
They walk through that door, you don't say nothing.
是她干的！是她干的！
She did it! She did it!
她才是你们要抓的人！
She's the one you want! All right?
我只是在家看卡通片
I was just sitting at home watching cartoons,
还有跟我堂弟玩游戏而已
playing video games with my cousin,
然后她闯了进来
and she came in there.
- 然后… - 格伦 你个混蛋
- And then… - Glen, you freak.
我才不会因为你或任何人去坐牢！
Hey! I am not going to jail for you or anybody else!
我这辈子从来没干过坏事！
I have done nothing bad my entire life!
老兄 我还是个童男呢！
Hey, man, I'm still a virgin.
好吧 那又怎样？
Okay, so what?
我是从互联网上…
I've downloaded a couple of…
下载了几千首歌
thousand songs off the Internet.
可是谁没有呢！
Who hasn't? Who hasn't?
- 我发誓！- 格伦 闭嘴！
- I promise! - Glen, shut up!
不 你闭嘴！不要跟我说话！
No, you shut up! Don't talk to me!
不要跟我说话 你这个罪犯！
Don't talk to me, criminal!
噢 给糖甜昏了头
Oh, sugar rush.
这不…这不是他的错
This is… This is not his fault.
听到了吗？我能回家了吗？
See? So can I go home now?
- 哦 好吧 我不会了 - 但请你听我说
- Oh, okay. I won't. - But just listen to me.
不管是谁黑了你们的防卫系统
Okay, whoever hacked into your military system…
并且下载了一个文件
downloaded a file, all right?
应该是跟一个名叫维特维奇的人有关
It was something about someone named Witwicky
还有一个政府组织
and some government group, right?
叫做第七区组织
Named Sector Seven.
请你让我先跟国防部长谈谈
You have to let me talk to Defense Secretary Keller…
否则你们很可能跟错误的敌人作战！
before you go to war with the wrong country!
不管天上掉了什么 它就落在…
Whatever fell out of the sky ended up right behind…
- 他怎么说？- 什么？
- What did he say? - What?
他也听到了吗？
Did he hear it, too?
是 杰克也听到了
Yeah, Jack heard it, too. Yeah.
他说是什么？
What does he think it is?
他以为是军事实验
He thinks it's a military experiment.
简直不知所谓
What a knucklehead.
对 我觉得是一架飞机…
Yeah, well, I think it's a plane.
- 目前官方尚未发布任何意见… - 耶
- Still no official word as to what happened. You… - Yeah.
打电话给山姆
Call Sam.
- 嗯 为什么？- 15分钟之内他该到家
- Yeah. Why? - He should be home in 15 minutes.
我15分钟之内打电话给他
Well, I'll call him in 15 minutes.
如果你再等15分钟
If you wait 15 minutes,
那他就晚了 你就得要禁他的足了
he'll be late and you'll have to ground him.
如果他没有晚 我就不能禁他 对吧？
Well, I can't ground him if he's not late, can I?
你就呆在这儿 知道吗？
I need you to stay here, all right?
你要呆在这儿看着他们
You got to stay here and you're gonna watch them.
- 好的 好的 - 所有的人
- Okay, okay. - All of them.
- 明白了吗？- 嗯 嗯 嗯
- Do you hear what I'm saying? - Yeah, okay, okay.
就5分钟 好吗？
Five minutes, all right?
谢谢你走在了入门径上
Thanks for staying on my path.
哦 不不 爸爸…嘿
Oh, yeah. No, no, Dad. Hey!
啊 入门径
The… Oh, the path.
对不起 我忘记了
I'm sorry. I forgot about the path.
我现在就打扫干净
I'm gonna sweep the whole thing right now.
怎么样？
How about that?
- 要知道我给你买了车… - 嗯
- You know, I buy half your car… - Yeah.
把你从警察局保释出来
then I bail you out of jail…
我还打算包了你所有的家务
and then I just decided to do all your chores.
- 家务… - 对啊 生活挺不错嘛 啊？
- The chores. - Yeah. Life is great, huh?
生活简直无与伦比 太棒了
Life… Life is fantastic, is how good it is.
哦 还有垃圾筒
It's so… Oh, the trash cans.
对不起 爸爸 我马上去倒
Sorry, Dad. I'm gonna do the trash cans now.
不 不 我不想累坏你
No, no, I don't want you to strain yourself.
不 不会累的 爸爸
No, no, I won't strain myself, Dad.
我去做
I'll do it.
如果你那样做 我会很伤心的
It would hurt my feelings if you do it.
- 你肯定？我不介意… - 我保证…
- You sure? I don't mind, I… - I promise…
不 不 不 我会去做的
No, no, no, I'm gonna do it.
我会去倒了垃圾
I'm gonna do the trash cans…
我还会擦洗烤架
and I'm gonna scrape the grill…
我还要…
and I'm gonna…
我马上就去打扫整个屋子
I'm gonna sweep up the whole house right now.
- 今晚 现在？- 对 现在！
- Tonight, right now? - Right now.
那…
The…
我爱你 爸爸
I love you. God, I love you,
我此时此刻真是太爱你了
just so much right now.
你妈妈要我把你关在家呢
You know, Mom wanted me to ground you.
- 你晚回家三分钟了 - 是吗？
- You're three minutes late. - Right?
哦 你看 你又为我做了一件事 爸爸！
Oh, well, just another thing you did for me, Dad,
你真是太好了
because you're such a swell guy,
又一件事 哈？
One more thing, huh?
好了 我爱你 睡个好觉 帅哥！
All right, I love you! Sleep good, handsome man!
你干嘛？你这是干嘛？
What are you doing? What are you doing?
不 注意门径 注意门径！
No, watch the path! Watch the path!
注意… 拜托 拜托 拜托
Watch the… Please, please, please.
- 不 等等 不 不！- 糟糕
- No, no, wait. No, no, no! Oh, no! - Oops.
- 对不起 我的错 - 啊 我…你不能…
- Sorry. My bad. - Oh, I… You couldn't…
你怎么连五分钟…
You couldn't wait for five…
你怎么连五分钟都等不了？
You couldn't wait for five minutes?
我说了 呆在那儿！呆在那儿！上帝！
I told you to just stay! Just stay! God!
我不是叫你看住他们！
I told you to watch them. I told you.
好的 你知道吗？
Okay, you know what?
他们就是这样急性子啊！
They seem to be in a little bit of a rush.
哦 太糟糕了 不！
Oh, this is bad. No!
魔球！魔球！别靠近机器人！
Mojo, Mojo! Off the robot! God!
- 啊 湿了 - 不 不 不 冷静 冷静！
- Oh, wet. - No, no, no, no, no! Easy! Easy!
住手 住手！这是魔球 这是魔球
Hold on! Hold! This is Mojo. This is Mojo.
是我的宠物
He's a pet of mine.
它是宠物 明白？
He's a pet. Okay? That's all.
如果你能收起你的武器…
If you could just put the guns away…
收起它们 拜托
Put the… Put them away. Please.
你有只啮齿动物
You have a rodent infestation.
- 一只什么？- 要不要摧毁？
- A what? - Shall I terminate?
不 不 不 它不是啮齿动物 它只是吉娃娃
No, no, no, no. He's not a rodent, he's a Chihuahua.
这是我的吉娃娃
This is my… This is my Chihuahua.
我们都爱吉娃娃 对不对？
We love Chihuahuas! Don't we?
他撒了我满脚润滑剂！
He's leaked lubricants all over my foot.
- 他在你脚上撒尿？坏魔球！坏魔球！- 坏魔球！
- He peed on you? Bad Mojo. Bad Mojo! - Bad Mojo!
对不起 它只是想表明这是它的领地
I'm sorry. He's got a male dominance thing.
仅此而已
That's all it is.
- 我的脚要生锈了 - 没事的
- My foot's gonna rust. - All right.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
- 闭嘴 去躲起来！- 快！
- Shut up and go hide! - Just hurry.
汽车人 进行侦察
Autobots, recon.
我希望他没事 他正在厨房里
I hope he's okay. He's in the kitchen.
在往他的鼻子上敷冰呢
Got some ice on his nose.
我刚刚小小地教训了他一下
I had to slap him around a little bit.
你才没有呢
You did not.
- 你甚至没有禁他足 - 差不多 差不多了
- You didn't even ground him. - Almost, almost.
他们在哪里？不 不 不
Where are they? No, no, no, no, no.
拜托 拜托
Come on, come on.
- 什么 这是什么？- 时间宝贵
- What? What is this? - Time is short.
他们真的很想要那副眼镜
They really want those glasses.
拜托 你在干什么？
Come on. What are you doing?
- 我想要帮你 - 好的
- I'm gonna help you. - Okay.
- 请快点 - 好的
- Please hurry. - Okay.
啊 不 真的不见了
Yeah, no, no. It's definitely gone.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
眼镜在袋子里
My glasses were in the bag.
袋子在我背包里
They were in the backpack…
但背包不在这里
and now the backpack isn't here.
他们肯定不会高兴的
Well, they're gonna be pissed,
现在怎么办？
so what do you wanna do?
我觉得你应该…
So what I think you should do is you should…
你应该清查下整个…
You should check this whole…
这里每个角落
This whole section here.
你帮我仔细找找
Just give it a clean sweep,
我找这边的角落
and I'll get the corner here.
不 不 那里不要
Yeah, no, no, no. Not there.
那边是我私人的…
That's my… That's my private…
- 对不起 没什么 - 你只是…
- Sorry. That's nothing. - You just…
- 你只是叫我找… - 我明白
- You just told me to look… - I know,
但我又没叫你…
but I didn't mean to look inside…
翻我的藏宝箱
of my treasure chest.
你应该讲清楚
You should be way more specific…
不然我又会找错地方…
so I don't get in trouble in your room.
我已经都快崩溃了
I'm already stressed out enough.
又怎么了？
Okay. What now?
不 不 不 不
No. No, no. No, no, no.
这算什么躲藏？这算什么躲藏？
This isn't hiding. This isn't hiding.
这里是我家后院 可不是公路休息站
This is my backyard, not a truck stop.
啊 上帝 啊！
Oh, God. Oh!
我看到了
Okay, I saw it.
不明飞行物体在此着陆 但现在不见了
The UFO landed right here and now it's gone.
我的摩托还在底下压着 伙计！
My moped's under there, man!
谁来赔我钱？
Who's gonna pay for that?
山姆？山姆 山姆
Sam? Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam.
他又来了
He's back here.
我处理不了 我…
I can't deal with this. I can't…
什么？噢 不 不
What? Oh, no, no, no.
- 糟糕 - 这是我妈的花园
- Oops. - This is my mother's flower…
好吧 听着 听我说
Okay, listen. You got to listen to me.
如果我父母出来看到了你们
If my parents come out here and see you,
他们会吓坏了的
they're gonna freak out.
我妈脾气很不好 好吗？
My mother's got a temper, okay?
我们必须拿到那副眼镜
We must have the glasses.
我知道你需要那副眼镜
I know you need the glasses.
我已经找遍所有地方
I've been looking everywhere.
它们不在这里 很明显不在这里
They're not here. They're definitely not here.
- 哦 继续找 - 听着
- Oh, keep searching. - Look…
我要你们安静五分钟
I need you to be quiet for five minutes.
或十分钟 好吗？
Ten minutes. Okay?
拜托 我求你们了
Please, I'm begging you.
你们要…你们太吵了
You got to… You're making a racket.
我不能专心
I can't concentrate.
你们要我找 我却听到…
You want me to look and I'm hearing…
冷静 冷静
Calm down, calm down.
你得帮帮我
You got to do something here.
汽车人 撤退
Autobots, fall back.
谢谢你 拜托 就五分钟
Thank you. Please, for five minutes.
好吗？好吗？
Good? Good? Okay
- 行动 - 走开！
- Move! - Get away!
你们怎么回事？就不能安静下吗？
What's the matter with you? Can't you be quiet?
他要我们安静
He wants us to be quiet.
地震了！快跑！地震了！
Earthquake! Move, move, move, move! Earthquake!
茱蒂 快躲到桌下！快呀！
Judy! Judy, get under the table! Move it!
赶快躲起来！
Duck and cover right now!
你怎么那么快就跑到那里？
How did you get over there so fast?
哇哦 好痒！
Wow! That was tingly!
- 你该试试！- 嗯 看上去很好玩
- You got to try that! - Yeah, that looks fun.
- 山姆？- 山姆？
- Sam? - Sammy?
- 那是什么？- 我不知道
- What the hell is that? - I don't know.
- 山姆？- 真奇怪
- Sam? - That's weird.
- 山姆！- 救护车 打开灯
- Sam! - Ratchet, point the light.
快点
Come on, hurry.
听着 这里出了点状况
Listen, we got a major issue in here.
开灯干什么 把灯关掉
What's with the light? You gotta stop the light.
怎么回事？把灯关掉
What's going on? Turn it off.
让他把灯关掉
You gotta tell him to shut it off.
- 关掉 - 山姆 你在里面吗？
- Shut it off. - Sam, are you in there?
为何门是锁着的？
How come the door's locked?
你知道规矩的 不许在家里锁门
You know the rules. No doors locked in my house!
你再不开门
You know he'll start counting…
- 他就要开始倒数了！- 最后一次机会 5…
- if you don't open the door! - One more chance. Five…
哦 天哪
Oh, dear.
- 4…打开门铰链 - 他在倒数了！
- Four. It's coming off the hinges, pal. - He's counting!
- 山姆 快开门 - 3
- Sam, just open the door. - Three.
- 噢 天啊 - 2
- Oh, my. - Two.
- 他在倒数 - 退后
- He's counting. - Stand back.
怎么了？你拿着球棒干嘛？
What's up? What's with the bat?
你刚在跟谁讲话？
Who were you talking to?
跟你们呀
I'm talking to you.
你怎么又臭又脏的？
Why are you so sweaty and filthy?
我年轻啊 你懂的 青少年嘛
I'm a child. You know, I'm a teenager.
我们听到有人声和噪音
We heard voices and noises…
我们以为你…
and we thought maybe you were…
我们怎么想不重要
It doesn't matter what we thought.
刚才那灯光是什么？
What was that light?
不是 什么灯光？没什么灯光 老爸！
No, what light? What? There's no light, Dad!
你们手上不就有两个手电筒！光是从你们这里来的
You got two lights in your hand! That's what it is.
- 或许就这么反射… - 光是从门缝里出来的
- Maybe it bounced… - There was light under the door
听我说 你们不…
Look, you can't…
你们不能就这么闯进我的房间里来
You can't just bounce into my room like that.
你应该先敲门 先沟通
You got to knock. You got to communicate.
- 我们敲了5分钟了 - 我长大了
- We knocked for five minutes. - I'm a teenager.
- 我们敲门了 - 你们没有
- We knocked. - You didn't knock.
- 你们是在冲我喊 知道吗？- 没有
- You were screaming at me, okay? - No.
你们现在是在打压我
This is repression, what you're doing here.
你们在蹂躏我的青春 知道吗？
You're ruining my youth, okay?
哦 老天啊
Oh, for Pete's sakes!
你太过激了 你在手淫吗？
You are so defensive! Were you masturbating?
- 茱蒂 - 我在…
- Judy. - Was I…
- 没有 老妈 - 够了 好吗？
- No, Mom. - Zip it, okay?
- 没关系的 - 没有 我没有手淫！
- It's okay. - No, I don't masturbate!
那不是你该管的
That's not something for you to bring up.
那是父子间的对话 好不好？
That's a father-and-son thing, okay?
父与子的私事
Father-son thing.
我是说 如果你不喜欢…
I mean, you don't have to call it that word…
这个词的话
if that makes you uncomfortable.
你可以称它为“山姆的快乐时间”
You can call it Sam's happy time or…
- 快乐时间？- 或“我特别的…”
- Happy time? - my special alone time…
- 别说了 - 老妈
- Stop. - Mom.
- 茱蒂 别说了 - “私人时间”
- Judy, stop. - with myself.
- 老妈 你不能就这么进来 - 对不起
- Mom, you can't come in and… - I'm sorry.
今晚有点不自在
It's just been a weird night.
我稍微喝了点酒
I've had a little bit to drink.
- 不要 老爸 - 好了 我们的确看到光的
- No, no, Dad. - Yeah, well, we saw a light.
哦 父母来了
Oh, parents.
我不知道在哪儿 但我的确看到了！
I don't know where it was, but we saw it.
地震！又来了！
Earthquake! It's another one!
又是地震！回到走廊里！
Another earthquake! Get in the doorway!
- 好的！- 余震！余震！
- Okay! - Aftershock! Aftershock!
哦 我不喜欢地震
Oh, I hate these.
- 安全第一 安全第一！- 快 藏起来
- Got to ride it out. Ride it out! - Quick, hide.
- 嘿 来电了 - 藏起来？什么？
- Hey, the lights are back on. - Hide? What?
- 藏哪儿？- 拜托 从浴缸里出来吧
- Where? - Come on, get out of that tub.
你不觉得保命很重要的？
Can't you take safety seriously?
要命 这地板真脏 山姆
Good Lord, this floor is filthy, Sam.
噢 不！你看院子 都毁了
Oh, no! Look at the yard. The yard is destroyed.
茱蒂 打给电力局
Judy? Better call the city.
变压器好像爆了
We got a blown transformer!
电杆火星四射！
Power pole's sparking all over the place!
哦 天哪 院子被毁了
Oh, man. Yard's a waste.
一塌糊涂 完了
Trashed. Gone.
- 成洼地了 整个花园 - 你开玩笑
- It's a wash. The whole yard. - You're kidding.
这对父母很烦人
The parents are very irritating.
- 是啊 是啊 - 我能不能处理掉他们？
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Can I take them out?
铁皮 你知道我们不能伤害人类的
Ironhide, you know we don't harm humans.
你在想什么？
What is with you?
我只是说我们是可以 只是一个方案
Well, I'm just saying we could. It's an option.
我们听到你和别人在说话 山姆
We heard you talking to somebody, Sam.
- 到底是谁？- 老妈 我说了…
- We wanna know who. - Mom, I told…
你好 我是梅卡拉
Hi. I'm Mikaela.
我是山姆的朋友
I'm a… I'm a friend of Sam's.
天啊 你真漂亮
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
她真是美若天仙 不是吗？
Isn't that the prettiest girl?
- 她听得到你说话 妈 - 谢谢你
- She can hear you talking, Mom. - Thank you.
天啊！真抱歉让你听到…
Oh, my goodness. I'm sorry you had to…
我们的家庭讨论…
hear our little family discussion about…
- 抱歉打扰你们了 - 妈 我的背包呢？
- Sorry that we're bugging you. - Do you have my backpack?
- 来 亲爱的 我们走 - 哦 在厨房里
- Come on, hon. Let's go. - Oh, it's in the kitchen.
哦 太好了
Oh, yes. Okay. Okay.
你妈人真好
Your mom's so nice.
你帮我分散我父母的注意
I want you to distract my parents while…
我就能溜出去把眼镜交给他们 好吗？
I slip out and get these glasses to them, okay?
- 罗纳德·维奇提？- 是维特维奇 你是谁？
- Ronald Wickity? - It's Witwicky. Who are you?
我们是政府机关 第七区的
We're the government. Sector Seven.
- 从来没听过 - 以后也不会
- Never heard of it. - Never will.
你儿子是…
Your son's the great-grandson…
阿奇巴尔德·维奇提的曾孙子 对不对？
of Captain Archibald Wickity, is he not?
是维特维奇
It's Witwicky.
我能进屋吗 先生？
May I enter the premises, sir?
荣恩 前院有好多人
Ron, there's guys all over the front yard.
到底是怎么回事？
What the heck is going on here?
你儿子昨晚举报有人偷车
Your son filed a stolen car report last night.
我们认为这关系到…
We think it's involved in…
国家的安全
a national security matter.
- 他们在拔我的玫瑰！- 国家安全？
- They're ripping up my rose bushes! - National security?
没错 国家安全
That's right. National security.
天哪 荣恩 到处都是他们的人
My God, Ron, they're everywhere.
到处都是穿西装的！
There's guys in suits all around the house!
看呀！
Look at this!
可不可以别踩我的草坪
Could you stay off the grass?
给我采取一些同位素的样本
Get me a sample and some isotope readings.
他们把树都拔了！
They're pulling bushes out of the ground!
老天！
Good Lord!
不许他们碰我的花！
They've got to get their hands off my bush!
- 请放下你的球棒 女士 - 喂喂喂 那是我的…
- Drop the bat, ma'am. - Hey, hey, hey, that's my…
我可是带着武器的
I'm carrying a loaded weapon.
你最好叫你的人离开我的花园
But you'd better get those guys out of my garden.
否则我会狠狠修理他们
or I am gonna beat the crap out of them!
你是否有流感的症状？
Are you experiencing any flu-like symptoms?
关节疼痛 发烧？
Aching joints? Fever?
- 没有 - 怎么回事？
- No! - What is this?
你好呀 小子 你叫山姆吗？
How you doing, son? Is your name Sam?
- 是啊 - 那你得跟我们走一趟
- Yeah. - Well, I need you to come with us.
喂 那可不行
Whoa, way out of line.
先生 我这已经很客气了 退下
Sir, I am asking politely. Back off.
- 你不能带我儿子走 - 是吗？
- You're not taking my son. - Really?
想和我们硬碰硬？
You gonna try to get rough with us?
不 但我会打电话报警 只因为…
No, but I'm gonna call the cops because…
这件事太点蹊跷
there's something fishy going on around here.
没错 这里是有些不对劲 你…
Yeah. There's something a little fishy about you,
你儿子 还有扣皮带的狗
your son, your little Taco Bell dog…
整个组织都有蹊跷
and this whole operation you got going on here.
什么组织？
What operation?
我们接下来就知道了
That is what we are gonna find out.
我认为是直接接触
I think direct contact.
- 孩子 - 嗯
- Son? - Yeah.
- 请上前来 - 站着就行？
- Step forward, please. - Just stand?
14单位
Fourteen rads.
找对人了！把他们贴上标签卷走
Bingo! Tag them and bag them!
你敢伤我的狗 我就揣你屁股
If you hurt my dog, I'll kick your ass!
- 尽快取得植被上的样本 - 山姆…
- Get me a sample on that vegetation ASAP! - Sam!
不要开口 山姆
Do not say anything, Sam!
- 好的 - 在律师来前一个字都别说！
- Yeah. - Not a word until we get a lawyer!
好了
So,
万人迷先生217
LadiesMan217…
那是你的易趣帐号名称 对吧？
That is your eBay username, right?
对 我打错字了 不过就将错就错
Yeah, but, you know, it was a typo and I ran with it.
那这是什么？
What do you make of this?
我叫山姆·维特维奇 知道吗？我的车…
My name is Sam Witwicky, okay? And my…
那是你吗？
Is that you?
是啊 那听起来像万人迷先生
Yeah, that sounds like LadiesMan.
昨晚在警局
Last night at the station,
你说你的车变形了
you told the officer your car transformed.
能不能解释一下
Enlighten me.
你听我说 好吗？
Well, here's what I said, okay?
我车被偷的这一切…
'Cause this is a total misunderstanding…
都是个误会
that my car had been stolen…
- 是吗？- 从我手上 从家里…
- Really? - from me, from my home,
但现在没事了 因为它回来了 已经回来了
but it's fine now because it's back! It came back!
- 不是自己回来的 - 当然不是
- Well, not by itself. - Well, no.
因为车子不会自己回来
Because cars don't do that…
因为那太荒唐了！
because that would be crazy!
真好笑 好笑
That's funny. That is so funny.
你们两个对外星人了解多少？
So what do you kids know about aliens, huh?
你说火星人？ET？不知道
Oh, you mean, like a Martian? Like what, E. T? No.
- 那只是个传说 - 是啊
- It's an urban legend. - Yeah.
知道这是什么吗？
You see this?
这是一枚…
This is an…
“为所欲为”徽章
I-can-do-whatever-I-want and-get-away-with-it badge.
- 是 - 我要把你们永远关起来
- Right. - I'm gonna lock you up forever.
哦 老天 我告诉你 别听他的
Oh, God. You know what? Don't listen to him.
他生气是因为他回去后
He's just pissy 'cause he's got to get back…
就得去作购物中心的保安
to guarding the mall.
你这穿着运动胸罩的 别惹我
You, in the training bra, do not test me.
尤其你爸的假释期快到了
Especially with your daddy's parole coming up.
什么？假释期？
What? Parole?
没什么
It's nothing.
哦 偷车大盗不算什么？
Oh, grand theft auto, that ain't nothing?
你知道我爸以前教我修的车…
You know those cars my dad used to teach me to fix?
那些…不全是他的
Well, they… They weren't always his.
你们偷车？
You stole cars?
我们有时请不起保姆
Well, we couldn't always afford a babysitter,
那时他就会带我一起去
so sometimes he had to take me along.
她也有少年犯罪前科
She's got her own juvie record to prove it!
她是个罪犯！性感的罪犯！
She's a criminal. Criminals are hot!
因为你不合作而让他…
That'd be a real shame if he had to…
下半辈子待在监狱不太好吧？
rot in jail the rest of his natural life.
该说实话了
It is time to talk!
真的好大
Big! It's big!
快 快 快 快！
Go, go, go, go!
我看不到！我看不到！
I can't see it! I can't see it!
你们把重心朝前！
Shift your weight towards the front!
够了！够了！
All right! All right!
你们这群废柴有麻烦了
You A-holes are in trouble now.
先生们 让我向你们介绍 我的朋友…
Gentlemen, I want to introduce you to my friend,
擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
带走这些孩子是错误的选择
Taking the children was a bad move.
汽车人 卸下他们的武器
Autobots, relieve them of their weapons.
不要动！
Freeze!
拿来吧
Give me those!
你好
Hi, there.
你好像不怕我们
You don't seem afraid.
难道你们看到我们不觉得惊讶吗？
Are you not surprised to see us?
第七区有规定 知道吗？
Look, there are S-Seven protocols, okay?
我不允许和你交流
I'm not authorized to communicate with you
不过除了告诉你“我不能和你交流”
except to tell you I can't communicate with you.
- 下车 - 好的
- Get out of the car. - All right.
- 我？你要我… - 下车！
- Me? You want me to get… - Now!
好的好的 下车
All right, all right. Get out. Hey.
好了 我…我在下了
All right, I'm… I'm getting out.
在下了 看到没？
I'm getting out. You see?
能那么放下我们…
Very nifty how you put us down…
却不让我们受伤 不错
without really killing us.
你对手铐也很在行吧？
You're good with handcuffs, too, now, huh?
你们好吗？
How you doing?
你不应该知道那些的
You weren't supposed to hear all that.
- 是啊 - 这都是真的
- Yeah. - This is real.
听好 如果我准备和他开战
Now, listen. If I choose to engage with him,
“妈妈”就是密语 知道吗？
mum is the word, all right?
山姆 我那前科是因为…
Sam, I have a record because…
我不肯供出我爸
I wouldn't turn my dad in.
在你完美的人生里
When have you had to sacrifice…
有过不得不作出牺牲的时候吗？
anything in your perfect little life?
大家伙 拿大炮的大家伙 嗯？
Big guys. Big guys with big guns, huh?
第七区是什么？回答我
What is Sector Seven? Answer me.
这里有权利发问的是我
I'm the one who asks questions around here.
不是你 小伙子！
Not you, young man!
你怎么知道外星人的事？
How'd you know about the aliens?
你把我父母带到哪去了？
Where did you take my parents?
- 我无权和你们讨论这些 - 是吗？
- I am not at liberty to discuss it. - No?
你碰我的话会触了联邦法
Hey. You touch me, that's a federal offense.
为所欲为的徽章 是吗？
Do-whatever-you-want and-get-away-with-it badge.
你现在有这些…
Yeah. Brave now all of a sudden,
外星人做靠山就大胆起来了
with his big alien friend standing over there.
第七区在哪儿？
Where is Sector Seven?
你们不想知道？
Wouldn't you like to know?
喂！
Hey!
大黄蜂 停止润滑他
Bumblebee, stop lubricating the man.
别闹了 好不好？
Get that thing to stop, huh?
好了 猛男 开始脱吧
All right, tough guy, take it off.
什么意思？
What are you talking about?
- 你的衣服 全脱了 - 为什么？
- Your clothes, all of it, off. - For what?
因为你威胁我爸
For threatening my dad.
小姑娘
Little lady,
这是你生命终结的序曲
this is the beginning of the end of your life.
你是个罪犯
You're a criminal.
面对现实吧 上梁不正下梁歪
Let's face facts. It's in your gene pool.
不错啊 站到路灯后面
Those are nice. Now get behind the pole.
知道了
All right.
你们这样做犯了很严重的罪
This is such a felony, what you're doing.
- 我会抓到你的 - 他抓到你的
- I will hunt you down, okay? - He'll hunt you down.
- 不会心软的 - 不会
- Without any remorse! - No remorse.
- 呆这吧 - 好了？
- Enjoy. - Okay?
我们必须通知所有人
We have got to alert everyone.
他们已经知道了 扩音器模式
They already know. Speaker.
擎天柱！敌人入侵！
Optimus! Incoming!
出发
Roll out.
我在那桥下测出…
Okay, I'm picking up rad readings…
有辐射反映
under that bridge right down there.
辐射反映很强
Okay, I'm getting really good rad readings.
超过42个单位
Forty-two and higher.
上来
Up you get.
好了 我们要行动了
Okay, we're dropping in.
我们下方辐射指数很高
Really strong readings right down below us.
他在那儿
There he is.
1号和2号船 到这儿来
Ship one and two, come on in.
看到了 在那儿 锁定他 锁定他
That's it, right there. Mark him, mark him.
他在那儿 正前方偏左 正下方
Okay, there he is. 11:30. Right off the nose.
看到了 正前方
I got it. 12:00.
好了 我在跟踪她 找到了
Okay, I'm tracking him. I've got him.
他正沿着街道移动
Got him going down the street.
他去哪儿了？我找不到他
Okay. Where'd he go, guys? I lost him.
失去红外信号 他去哪儿了？
Got no IR signature. Where'd he go?
信号丢失 信号丢失
Okay, I lost him. I lost him.
我们这就赶过去
Okay, we're coming around.
小心点 你们俩
Easy, you two.
不！不！山姆！山姆！别放手
No! No! No, Sam! Sam, don't drop me!
山姆 不要！我在往下滑！
Sam, don't! Sam, don't! I'm slipping! I'm slipping!
- 抓住！- 不要
- Hold on! - No!
山姆！
Sam!
我们找到了他了
All right, we've got him pinned.
目标锁定在河上
We've got him pinned in the river.
进入射击范围
I'm in for the shot.
住手！住手！
Stop! Stop!
等等！不要！
Wait! No!
- 射击 抓住他 - 射击
- Take the shot, get him. - Take the shot.
不要！
No!
不要！住手！
No! Stop!
住手！
Stop!
趴在地上！趴下！
Get down on the ground! Get down! Get down!
什么？好的
What? Okay.
看啊 他没有还手
Look, he's not fighting back!
冻住它！冻住它！
Freeze it! Freeze it! Freeze it!
不要伤害他！
Stop hurting him!
让他别动！
Don't let him move!
我抓住他了
I got him here!
不要！
No!
看到我开不开心？
Happy to see me again?
把他和他的罪犯朋友关到车子里
Put him in a car with his little criminal friend.
把那东西冷冻起来准备运送
I want that thing frozen and ready for transport!
退后 我去侦查一下
Hang back. Let me check it out.
擎天柱
Optimus,
我们就待在这儿什么都不做？
are we just gonna stand here and do nothing?
我们没办法为救大黄蜂…
There's no way to free Bumblebee…
而不伤害人类
without harming the humans.
- 但这成何体统 他… - 让他们走吧
- But it's not right. He… - Let them leave.
中国和俄国 非常接近我们的…
The Chinese and the Russians are nearing our
西太平洋作战区 这局势…
area of operations in the western Pacific.
我们控制不了多久
We feel like this could get out of hand real fast.
接下来数小时…
But the next couple of hours…
就看他们总统怎么做了
may just define his presidency.
有中国特遣舰队已经接近…
US and Chinese task forces approaching…
巡弋飞弹射程100英里之内
100 nautical miles of cruise missile range.
告诉航母指挥官
Tell the strike group commander…
除非对方先进攻 否则不要攻击
that he's not to engage unless fired on first.
- 是的 长官 - 部长先生？
- Yes, sir! - Mr. Secretary?
我是汤姆·班奈杰克 隶属第七区
Tom Banachek. I'm with Sector Seven,
先进研究部的
Advanced Research Division.
从没听说过
Never heard of it.
我现在很忙 汤姆 我想你也看得出来
I'm a little busy, Tom. I think you can see that.
- 怎么回事？- 不知道
- What's going on here? - I don't know.
情况通报员！出来说句话！
Sit rep! Talk to me!
整间作业都中断了 先生
The whole room's gone down, sir.
我看得出来！
I can see that!
病毒是用来中断所有作业的
The virus was coded to shut us down.
- 将军？- 我坐在那里等
- General? - I'll take a seat.
中止作业是什么意思？
What do you mean, "shut us down"?
它们利用我们网站
They used our network…
把病毒散布出去
to spread out to the whole world.
全球性的网络
The blackout's global.
我们与全球的卫星
We have no communications,
固网联络都中断了
satellite and land lines are dead.
你是说我无法用这台电话…
You mean to tell me that I cannot pick up this telephone…
打给我家里？
and call my family?
部长先生
Mr. Secretary?
我是奉总统之命而来
I'm here under direct order from the President.
你需要看看我这手提箱里的东西
You really need to see what I have in the case.
你必须知道有些事情
You'll have to accept that there are certain things
你无法立即了解
you won't understand right away.
第七区是政府内…
Sector Seven is a special-access…
一个特殊部门 它的成立…
division of the government, convened in…
是80年前奉胡佛总统之密令成立的
secret under President Hoover 80 years ago.
您可能记得太空总署和喷推实验室
You may remember NASA JPL…
在火星上损失了猎犬二号机器人
lost the Beagle 2 Mars Rover.
我们告诉他们将整件任务…
We told them to report the mission…
宣告失败 其实不然
a complete failure. It wasn't.
猎犬二号传输了十三秒钟的影像
Beagle 2 transmitted 13 seconds.
这是比最高机密还要机密的
This was classified above top secret.
电子活动在170小时48分后停止
EDA ended at 170 hours, 48 minutes.
火星上不是只有石头
More than just a pile of Martian rocks.
这是火星上传来的影像
This is the image from Mars.
这是您的特种部队
Here's the image your Special Ops team
在基地被袭击时拍得的影像
was able to retrieve from the base attack.
我们相信这是相同的外骨骼结构
We believe they are of the same exoskeletal type,
很显然地并非俄国或北朝鲜能有的
and obviously not Russian or North Korean.
你是说外星入侵？
Are we talking about an invasion?
我们拦劫了…
We intercepted the message…
特种部队传来的讯息
from your Special Ops team.
那些东西知道…
These things can be hurt…
他们也能被我方武器损伤
by our weapons and now they know it.
所以他们用病毒使军事指挥陷入瘫痪
That's why the virus shut us down,
好让我们无法组织防备他们下一波攻击
so we can't coordinate against their next attack,
我敢用我的政府薪金打赌
which I would bet my ridiculous…
下一波攻击绝对会很快来临
government salary is coming soon.
用国民警卫队的频道…
Get word to our fleet commanders…
通知舰队指挥官
over the National Guard frequency.
那是短波
It's a shortwave radio channel.
可能还有作用
It might be still working.
叫他们调转船头 迅速赶回来
Tell them to turn their ships around and come home.
通知各司令部
And inform all commands…
抵抗即将发生的攻击
to prepare for imminent attack.
（内利斯空军基地）
伦诺克斯上尉
Captain Lennox,
请带你的部队跟我们来！
we need you and your team to come with us right now!
我们走！
Let's go!
她在这里
She's in here.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
你跟我来
You're coming with me.
- 你来做我的顾问 - 我也要去？
- You're going to be my advisor. - Me, too?
他是谁？
Who's this?
- 他是我的顾问 - 那他也来
- He's my advisor. - He comes, too.
- 那么… - 他们要你们来做什么？
- So… - What'd they get you for?
我买了辆车…结果是个外星机器人
I bought a car. Turned out to be an alien robot.
谁知道呢
Who knew?
走直线！小心你身后！
Make a hole! Watch your back!
拜托 希望有用
Please, let this work.
启动吧 擎天柱
Fire it up, Optimus.
代码
The code.
眼镜里的代码显示…
The code on these glasses indicates…
火种源在离这里230英里远处
the All Spark is 230 miles from here.
我感觉到霸天虎…
I sense the Decepticons…
已准备开始行动了
are getting ready to mobilize.
他们一定也知道火种源在这里
They must know it's here, as well.
大黄蜂怎么办？
What about Bumblebee?
我们不能就这么失去他…
We can't just leave him to die…
眼睁睁的被人类当作试验品
and become some human experiment!
如果我们不完成任务的话
He'll die in vain…
他的牺牲就白费了
if we don't accomplish our mission.
大黄峰是名勇敢的战士
Bumblebee is a brave soldier.
这会是他所希望的
This is what he would want.
为何我们为拯救人类而战？
Why are we fighting to save the humans?
他们是个原始且残暴的种族
They're a primitive and violent race.
我们以前不也是吗？
Were we so different?
他们是个年轻的种族 还有很多要学
They're a young species. They have much to learn.
但我看到过他们的优点
But I've seen goodness in them.
自由是所有有情感的生物之希望
Freedom is the right of all sentient beings.
你们都知道结束这战争只有一个方法
You all know there's only one way to end this war.
我们必须消灭能量体
We must destroy the Cube.
如果其它方法都失败的话
If all else fails,
我会将它与我胸中之火光结合
I will unite it with the spark in my chest.
那是自杀行为
That's suicide.
能量体的能源非常不稳定 可能会玉石俱焚
The Cube is raw power. It could destroy you both.
为这星球的和平 牺牲是难免的
A necessary sacrifice to bring peace to this planet.
我们不能让人类为我们的错误而偿命
We cannot let the humans pay for our mistakes.
很荣幸与你们共战至今
It's been an honor serving with you all.
- 汽车人 出发！- 出发！
- Autobots, roll out! - We rolling!
立正！敬礼！
Team attention! Present arms!
上尉 军士 请稍息
At ease. Captain, Sergeant.
得到你的情报了 干得好
Got your intel. Excellent work.
谢谢 炮艇机呢？
Thank you, sir. What about the gunships?
所有炮艇机上加装了脱壳穿甲弹
They're being retrofitted with sabot rounds now.
如果他们再来袭击 没问题的
If they hit us again, we'll be ready for them.
但是不恢复全球的通讯
But it won't do us much good…
可真是不太妙
if we can't get world communications back up.
嘿 小子
Hey, kid.
我想我们之前有点误会
I think we got off to a bad start, huh?
你一定饿了吧？
You must be hungry?
要不要来杯拿铁咖啡 或者2份超大的玛琪朵咖啡如何？
You want a latte? HoHo? Double venti macchiato?
我的车呢？
Where's my car?
小子 你仔细听好
Son, I need you to listen to me very carefully.
这里人们的生命有危险
People can die here.
你必须马上告诉我们…
We need to know everything you know.
你所知道的
We need to know it now.
好吧
Okay.
但你得先把我的车和我父母还我
But first, I'll take my car, my parents.
全部要书面保证
Maybe you should write that down.
噢 还有她的少年前科
Oh, and her juvie record.
也必须取消 永久地
That's got to be gone. Like, forever.
跟我来 我们谈谈你的车
Come with me. We'll talk about your car.
谢谢
Thank you.
这小子简直是勒索
The man's an extortionist.
情况是这样的
All right, here's the situation.
你们都曾直接接触过NBEs
You've all had direct contact with the NBEs.
NBEs？
NBEs?
“非生物类外星人”
Non-Biological Extraterrestrials.
记清楚了
Try and keep up with the acronyms.
你们即将看到的是高度机密
What you're about to see is totally classified.
天啊 这是什么？
Dear God. What is this?
我们认为
We think…
当他飞越北极时
when he made his approach over the north pole,
地球的地心引力扰乱了他的导航系统
our gravitational field screwed up his telemetry.
他坠落到冰里
He crashed in the ice,
大概是几千年前的事
probably a few thousand years ago.
我们在1934年将它运送到这里
We shipped him here to this facility in 1934.
我们称它为NBE-1
We call him NBE One.
抱歉 先生 我不是想…
Well, sir, I don't mean to correct you…
故意纠正你的错误
on everything you think you know,
但那是威震天
but, I mean, that's Megatron.
他是霸天虎的领袖
He's the leader of the Decepticons.
它自从1935年就处在冰冻状态
He's been in cryostasis since 1935.
你的曾曾祖父发现了
Your great-great-grandfather made one of…
人类史上最大的发现
the greatest discoveries in the history of mankind.
事实上 你所看到的…
Fact is, you're looking at…
就是现代化的来源
the source of the modern age,
微晶片 雷射 太空飞行
the microchip, lasers, spaceflight,
汽车…都是对它进行逆向工程所习得的
cars, all reverse-engineered by studying him.
NBE-1 那是我们对它的称呼
NBE One. That's what we call it.
你不认为…
And you didn't think the…
美国军方需要知道
United States military might need to know
你把一个外星机器人…
that you're keeping a hostile…
冰冻在地下室？
alien robot frozen in the basement?
在最近发生的事之前
Until these events,
我们并不认为它会对国家安全产生威胁
we had no credible threat to national security.
现在问题可大了
Well, you got one now.
- 但为何要来地球？- 因为火种源
- So why Earth? - It's the All Spark.
火种源？那是什么？
All Spark? What is that?
他们在找一个…
Well, yeah, they came here looking for…
立方体似的东西
some sort of cube-Iooking thing.
NBE-1 也就是威震天先生
Anyway, Mr. NBE One here, AKA Megatron,
他们这样称呼他
that's what they call him,
他是死亡的使者
who's pretty much the harbinger of death,
想利用能量体转化
wants to use the Cube to transform…
人类科技来统治宇宙
human technology to take over the universe.
那就是他们的计划
That's their plan.
- 你很确定？- 是的
- And you're sure about that? - Yeah.
你们知道那东西在哪里 是不是？
You guys know where it is, don't you?
跟我来
Follow me.
你们将看到的东西是终极至宝
You're about to see our crown jewel.
碳-14年代测定预估能量体 是在公元前一万年来到地球的
Carbon dating puts the Cube here around 10, 000 BC.
七元老在1913年才发现它
The first Seven didn't find it until 1913.
他们知道这是外星物体 是因为…
They knew it was alien because of…
它表面的烙画
the matching hieroglyphics on the Cube
和NBE-1表面的烙画非常相似
as well as NBE One.
胡佛总统因此建造了水坝将它隐藏于其中
President Hoover had the dam built around it.
四个足球场厚度的水泥…
Four football fields thick of concrete
任何人或外面的…
A perfect way to hide its energy…
任何外星种族
from being detected by anyone…
都无法侦测出它所散发的能量
or any alien species on the outside.
火种源位置确定
我是红蜘蛛 所有霸天虎 准备行动
路障上路
吵闹报到…
袭击出发…
眩晕入列…
威震天万岁！
等等
Wait, back up.
你说水坝隐藏了他的能量
You said the dam hides the Cube's energy.
- 哪种能量？- 问得好
- What kind exactly? - Good question.
请进来 他们要把我们锁在里面
Please step inside. They have to lock us in.
喔
Oh, wow.
这是什么？
What's that?
佛瑞迪来过这里吗？
Freddy Krueger done been up in here or something?
不对
Oh, no, man.
佛瑞迪有四根爪子
Freddy Krueger have four blades, man.
那只有三根 那是金刚狼
That's only three. That's Wolverine!
- 对不对？那是金刚狼 - 很好笑
- Right? That's Wolverine! - That's very funny.
谁有电子产品？
Anybody have any mechanical devices?
黑莓？车钥匙？手机？
BlackBerry? Key alarm? Cell phone?
我有个手机
I got a phone.
诺基亚真是酷毙了
Nokias are real nasty.
你必须要佩服日本人
You've got to respect the Japanese.
他们将武士道发挥地淋漓尽至
They know the way of the samurai.
诺基亚是芬兰做的
Nokia's from Finland.
没错 但他…有点奇怪
Yes, but he's, you know, a little strange.
有点奇怪
He's a little strange.
我们把能量体的能源
We're able to take the Cube radiation…
传送到这箱子里
and funnel it into that box.
好凶的小东西
Mean little sucker, huh?
好可怕！
That thing is freaky!
就像劲量的…
Kind of like the itty-bitty…
兔宝宝一样
Energizer Bunny from hell, huh?
它快把箱子打破了
He's breaking the box.
行动！行动！
Go! Go! Go!
出发！
Move!
各位 他们知道能量体在这里
Gentlemen, they know the Cube is here.
班奈杰克 发生什么事了？
Banachek. What's going on?
NBE-1停机棚断电了
Well, the NBE One hangar has lost power…
- 什么？- 备用发电机…
- What? - and the backup generator…
无法产生足够电量
is just not gonna cut it.
你有没有军火库
Do you have an arms room?
威震天！威震天！威震天！
Megatron! Megatron! Megatron!
带上保安人员…
I'll bring security to the…
把所有人派去NBE-1停机棚！
Get everyone to the NBE One chamber now!
- 灯灭了！- 行动！
- The lights are out! - Move it! Move it!
快！
Let's go!
它们在攻击我们的发电机！
They're popping our generators!
（冷冻失效）
（表面温度）
威震天冰在融化！
Megatron melting!
16502 我们在失压
16502. We're losing pressure.
各就各位！
Stand by! Set!
失压…失压
We're losing pressure!
冷冻系统失常
The cryogenic system is failing!
我们失去NBE-1了
We're losing NBE One!
40毫米穿甲弹在那桌上
Forty millimeter sabot rounds on that table!
你必须带我去我的车
You got to take me to my car.
You have to take me to my car.
它知道怎么处理能量体
He's gonna know what to do with the Cube.
你的车？被没收了
Your car? It's confiscated.
那就别没收它
Then unconfiscate it.
我们不知道让它接近能源体…
We do not know what will happen…
会发生什么事！
if we let it near this thing!
是你不知道
You don't know.
也许你知道 但我不知道
Maybe you know, but I don't know.
你就准备呆在这儿…
You just wanna sit here…
坐以待毙？
and wait and see what happens?
很多人的生命掌握在我们手上
I have people's lives at stake here, young man.
让他去见他的车！
Take him to his car!
放下武器
Drop it.
喔！喔！喔！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
放下你的武器 军人
Drop your weapon, soldier.
外星人已经发动战争了
There's an alien war going on…
而你却要杀我？
and you're gonna shoot me?
我们没必要杀你
You know, we didn't ask to be here.
我以第七区的权力…
I'm ordering you under S-Seven…
命令你放手
executive jurisdiction.
第七区并不存在
S-Seven don't exist.
我们不会听命于…
Right. And we don't take orders…
一个不存在的组织
from people that don't exist.
我数到五
I'm gonna count to five. Okay.
我数到三
Well, I'm gonna count to three.
- 西门斯？- 是 先生
- Simmons? - Yes, sir?
我会照他说的做
I'd do what he says.
输不是他们这些人的选项
Losing's really not an option for these guys.
好吧 好吧
All right. Okay.
你想把世界的命运
Hey, you want to lay the fate of the world
交给这小子的车 那好吧
on the kid's Camaro? That's cool.
住手！住手！
No, no!
住手！住手！住手！
Stop! You got to stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
住手！住手！住手！放开他！
No, no, stop, stop, stop! Let him go! Let him go!
你没事吗？
Are you okay?
他们没伤你吧？
They didn't hurt you, right?
听我说 能量体在这里
Listen to me. The Cube is here…
霸天虎已经来了
and the Decepticons are coming.
不 不 别管他们 好吗？
No, don't worry about them. They're okay. Right?
他们不会伤你的
They're not gonna hurt you.
退后一点 他没有恶意
Just back up a little bit. He's friendly. He's fine.
好了 来吧
Okay, come on.
放下枪 他们不会伤害你的
Put the guns down. They're not gonna hurt you.
跟我来
Here, come with me.
我带你去看火种源
I'm gonna take you to the All Spark.
好呀 来了
Okay, here we go.
他要做什么了 他要做了
He doing something. He doing something.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
来自太空舰队的消息
Message from Starfleet, Captain.
把这个带走
Let's get to it.
他说的对 我们要是留下来
He's right. We stay here,
就死定了 威震天就在隔壁的机棚里
we're screwed with Megatron in the other hangar.
最近的城市在22英里外
Mission City is 22 miles away.
我们把能量体偷带出去
We're gonna sneak that Cube out of here
然后藏在城市里
and we're gonna hide it somewhere in the city.
很好 就这么做
Good! Right.
但我们需要空军的帮忙
But we cannot make a stand without the Air Force.
这地方一定有无线电装置吧
This place must have some kind of radio link!
- 是的 - 短波 - 对 有
- Yes. - Shortwave, CB. - Right, yes.
先生 你一定要想办法
Sir, you got to figure out some way…
传递消息出去 我们走
to get word out to them. Let's move!
是非常旧的仪器
In the alien archive, sir!
之前陆军使用的
There's an old Army radio console.
- 还能用吗？- 一切皆有可能！
- Will it work? - Anything's possible!
你看到…
Did you see that…
好了 山姆 上车！
All right, Sam, get it in the car!
部长先生 请继续试着联络空军
Mr. Secretary! Get our birds in the air.
等我们到了城市我们再找个无线电
When we get to the city, we're gonna find a radio,
让艾普斯无线电导引 好吗？
and I'll have Epps vector them in, okay?
收到
Affirmative!
警告 NBE-1冷冻系统故障
Warning! NBE One cryo-containment failing.
检查备用系统！
Check that backup system!
快点逃出这里！
Come on! Get out of here!
抬头！小心！
Heads up! Look out!
大家帮黄车开一条路
Set a perimeter around the yellow vehicle!
这边！这边！
This way, this way, this way!
就在那！走！
Up there! Let's go!
我是威震天！
I am Megatron!
- 能量体没事吧？- 嗯 没事
- The Cube's okay? - Yeah, it's fine.
系上安全带
Well, put the seat belt on.
弄到他身上！
Pour it on him!
很荣幸为您效劳 威震天
I live to serve you, Lord Megatron.
能量体呢？
Where is the Cube?
被人类拿走了
The humans have taken it.
你又让我失望了 红蜘蛛 抓住他们
You fail me yet again, Starscream. Get them!
用力！
Come on, Mags!
在这边 先生！
Over here, sir!
等一下 等一下
Give me a minute. Give me a minute.
拜托 拜托 插在这
Come to me, Maxwell, come to me. Plugged in there.
- 通了 有电了！- 麦克风在哪？
- We're hot! We're live! - Where are the mikes?
麦克风！
Mikes?
没麦克风也没用
This doesn't work without mikes, Simmons.
不 不 不 不！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
快找找
Let's find them.
小子 你坐下
Kid, get in the chair!
你坐下 好吗？
Just get in the chair, all right?
他们把什么都偷走了
They steal everything out of this place.
我们要怎么传出讯号？
How do we get the signal out?
我们怎么联络空军？
How do we call the Air Force?
- 格伦？- 嗯？
- Glen? - Huh?
格伦 你能否把这台电脑…
Can you hotwire this computer…
接上无线电 然后送出讯号？
to transmit a tone through the radio?
那有什么用？
What good is that?
你可以把这台电脑连上无线电
Morse code! You can use this…
然后传送莫尔斯电码！
to transmit it through that!
好 好！我可以！快点 我看看
Okay, I'll do it! Turn it around. Okay, let's see.
西门斯 我要个螺丝刀
Simmons, I need a screwdriver!
擎天柱来了
There's Optimus.
快好了
Almost done.
那是什么玩意？
What the hell was that?
把门堵住！
Barricade the door!
- 找些东西 - 小心！
- Get something. - Watch out!
六 五 四 六 三
Six, five, four, six, three.
拿着！装弹！
Here! Put some rounds in!
全局搜索…
Master search.
我成功了 正在发送
I got it! We're transmitting!
照我说的写
Send exactly what I say!
闪开！快闪开！
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
烧死你！你个小杂碎！
Burn, you little sucker! Burn!
这里是国防部长凯勒…
"This is Defense Secretary Keller.
致北方司令部长官
"Get me NORTHCOM commander."
- 喔！- 喔！
- Whoa! - Whoa!
刚才是什么啊！
What was that?
启动紧急步骤 黑鸟1195…
Authenticate emergency action. Blackbird 1195…
长官 我们确认来自…
Sir, I have an authenticated…
国防部长的空袭命令
ir strike order from Sec Def.
- 不 不 不 - 怎么？
- No, no, no, no, no. - What?
还是那辆警车！
It's the same cop!
挡住他们！
Block them, block them, block them.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
真酷 妈妈！
Cool, Mom!
情况不妙
This is so not good.
他在柱子后面！
He's behind the pillar!
- 打死他 - 玛吉 掩护！
- Shoot that mother… - Maggie, cover fire!
空军已经回应
It's the Air Force! They're responding!
烧死你！
Sucker, burn!
哦 糟糕！
Oh, shit!
他们派F-22到城市去了！
Yes! They're sending F-22s to the city!
猛禽 出动！出动！出动！
Raptors, let's scramble, scramble, scramble.
攻击机群整队
Strike and Dark Star roll call.
（当铺）
来吧 快走！行动！
Come on, let's go! Mount up!
给你 短波无线电
Here, I got shortwave radios.
等等 我怎么用这玩意？
Wait. What am I supposed to do with these?
用它联系 只有这个了！
Well, use them! It's all we got!
这个像是…
This is like RadioShack…
中古电器行的古董了
dinosaur radios or something, man.
范围最多…
I'm only gonna get 20 or 30 miles…
20-30英里
out of these things.
呼叫城市上方的飞机
Are there any aircraft orbiting the city?
12点方向 F-22战斗机
F-22 at 12:00
好的 请求飞机空中掩护
All right, I want planes for air cover…
让黑鹰直升机来
and get Black Hawks on station…
运送能量体
to extract that Cube. You got it?
空军到了 放烟雾信号
Air Force has arrived! Pop smoke!
猛禽猛禽 能否听到
Raptor, Raptor, do you copy?
能看到你们
We have you visual.
标记是绿色烟雾
Green smoke is the mark.
请提供空中掩护
Provide air cover…
黑鹰机来接我们
and vector Black Hawks for extraction.
是红蜘蛛！
It's Starscream!
请回应我
Please tell me you copy.
退后 掩护 大黄蜂！
Back up! Take cover! Bumblebee!
不 不 不 快躲开！
No, no, no, no, no! Move!
- 后退 后退！- 快撤！
- Back up! Back up! - Retreat! Fall back!
来了！
Incoming!
有人受伤吗？大家没事吧？
Anybody hurt? Everyone okay?
清场！
Clear the area!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
大黄蜂 你的腿！
Bumblebee? No. Your legs!
你的腿！
Your legs.
后退 后退！你没事吧？
Here. Here, back, back, back, back! You all right?
拜托 大黄蜂 快起来！
Please get up. Bumblebee? Get up!
救护车！
Ratchet!
刚才怎么回事？
What the hell was that?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
什么我什么意思？
What do you mean, what am I talking about?
他们向我们开火！
They shot at us!
F-22不可能飞得比房子还低
F-22 pilots would never fly below buildings.
刚才那个是外星人 不是自己人！
That's alien. That ain't friendly!
你要站起来 你没事的
You got to get up. You're okay. You're okay.
加油！
Come on!
直升机接近中 请提供确切方位
Army Black Hawk inbound to your location. Over.
A273度 10英里
Alpha 273 degrees, 10 miles.
N40 往北1.2公里
November Victor, 1.2 clicks north.
快 行动！
Move out! Let's go!
快点！
Let's go! Move!
我不会离开你的
I'm not gonna leave you.
来啊 霸天虎坏蛋！
Come on, Decepticon punk!
哦 天啊！
Oh, my God!
集中火力
Concentrate your fire!
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
威震天！
Megatron!
是威震天 快撤退！
It's Megatron! Retreat! Move! Fall back!
撤退！
Fall back!
快让我们的人离开这！快！
Get our guys out of the way! Get out of here! Go!
离开这辆车！
Get them out of the buggy! Move out!
我们需要空中支援 马上要！
We need air cover down here now!
山姆 过来帮我
Sam, help me with this.
就这点本事 威震天？
That all you got, Megatron?
过来 小杂种
Come here, little cretin.
你想尝尝厉害么？
You want a piece of me? You want a piece?
不 来个双份的！
No! I want two!
怎么回事？
What's going on?
长官 那坦克又起来了
Sir! That tank thing's getting back up.
哦 这些家伙怎么不死呢
Oh, these things just don't die.
哦 我们惨了
Oh, we're so dead.
- 扣在头部！- 山姆！
- Wrap it around the head. - Sam!
能量体呢？
Where's the Cube?
- 就在这 - 好的
- Right there. - Okay.
把它拿过去绕在底盘
And take that and wrap it around
然后围在脖子上
the base and then put it around his neck.
- 明白吗？- 艾普斯 让那些黑鹰战机过来！
- Okay? - Epps, get those Black Hawks here!
那座楼
That building.
- 好了 - 什么？
- Okay. - What?
我不能让我的人留在那
All right, I can't leave my guys back there,
你拿着信号弹
so here, take this flare.
那边有个白色大楼
Okay, there's a tall, white building…
上面有雕塑的
with statues on top.
- 到楼顶去 拉开信号弹 - 不
- Go to the roof. Set the flare. - No.
打开信号弹通知直升机
Signal the chopper and set the flare.
不 不 我做不到
No, no. I can't do this!
听着！你现在是个战士！
Listen to me! You're a soldier now!
我要你带走能量体
All right? I need you to take this Cube.
送回军方手里 这里我们顶着
Get it into military hands while we hold them off,
否则会死很多人的
or a lot of people are gonna die.
你快走 你快走
You got to go. You got to go.
不 我不走
No, I'm not leaving.
- 你得走了 - 不 我不走
- You need to go. Go. - No, I'm not leaving
大黄蜂不走 我就不能走
till I get Bumblebee out of here, okay?
呼叫黑鹰直升机
Army Black Hawk requested.
请求立刻送走一个男孩和重要物品
Immediate evac for civilian boy with precious cargo.
他在房顶上 有信号弹
Headed to rooftop marked by flare.
- 山姆 我们会掩护你的 - 好吧
- Sam, we will protect you. - Okay.
- 艾普斯 飞机呢？- 山姆！
- Epps, where are those planes? - Sam!
无论结局会怎样
No matter what happens,
我都很高兴那天上了你的车
I'm really glad I got in that car with you.
山姆！快行动！
Sam! Get to the building! Move!
- 霸天虎 进攻！- 开火！
- Decepticons, attack! - Hit it!
火力掩护！
Cover fire!
小心！
Watch out!
快把车开走！
Girl, get that tow truck out of here!
马上就走！
I'm going! I'm going!
赶快走！
Get out of here now!
威震天！
Megatron!
擎天柱
Prime.
人类不配活着
Humans don't deserve to live.
这要由人类自己决定
They deserve to choose for themselves.
跟他们一起去死吧！
Then you will die with them!
一同毁灭！
Join them in extinction!
继续跑 山姆！
Keep moving, Sam!
别停！
Don't stop!
不！
No!
山姆 快去大楼！
Sam, get to the building!
把能量体给我 孩子！
Give me that Cube, boy!
那个臭小子不会把我车撞瘪了吧？
Did that jerk just dent my car?
你抓不到我的 你抓不到我的！
You're not gonna get me. You're not gonna get me!
我闻到你了 臭小子！
I smell you, boy!
小杂种！
Maggot!
哦 不！
Oh, no!
我开车 你开枪！
I'll drive! You shoot!
情况不妙
This isn't going well!
开枪 开枪
Shoot! Shoot!
打得好
Nice shot.
那坦克这次肯定死了
That tank is definitely dead now.
大家继续战斗
All right, let's go! We got business!
嘿！
Hey!
嘿！我在这！
Hey! I'm over here!
找到男孩了
We've got the boy.
小心！
Watch out!
导弹！
Missile!
撑住 山姆！
Hang on, Sam!
不！不！
No! No!
这到底是恐惧还是勇气控制着你？
Is it fear or courage that compels you, fleshling?
该怎么办？
Where do I go?
把火种源给我 我饶你不死 当我的宠物
Give me the All Spark and you may live to be my pet.
不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
我绝对不会给你这个火种源！
I'm never giving you this All Spark!
哦 真愚钝
Oh, so unwise.
接住你了 小子
I got you, boy.
抱紧能量体！
Hold on to the Cube!
- 哦…不… - 真恶心
- Oh, no. Oh, no! - Disgusting.
山姆
Sam.
你用你的生命保护了能量体
You risked your life to protect the Cube.
没有付出…
No sacrifice…
- 就没有胜利 - 如果杀不了威震天
- no victory. - If I cannot defeat Megatron,
你一定要把能量体塞入我的胸膛
you must push the Cube into my chest.
我会牺牲自己 与它同归于尽
I will sacrifice myself to destroy it.
躲到我身后去
Get behind me.
只有你我两个的决斗了 威震天
It's you and me, Megatron.
不 只有我 擎天柱
No, it's just me, Prime.
决战结束时
At the end of this day,
胜者为王 败者为寇
one shall stand, one shall fall.
你仍然在为弱者而战 所以你必输无疑
You still fight for the weak! That is why you lose!
战机60秒后到
Fighter jets in 60 seconds.
两派机器人都有
We got friendlies mixed with bad guys.
我们会用激光标记敌人
Targets will be marked.
嘿！
Hey!
呼叫空袭 明白？
Bring the rain. All right?
我们来消灭这些东西
All right, let's kill these things.
- 快走！- 记住 向下瞄准
- Move, move, move! - Remember, aim low.
盔甲的弱点在胸部下面
Armor's weak under the chest.
目标已被标出 等待中
Target marked. Still waiting.
20秒钟到达目标
Time on target, 20 seconds.
F-22战机 我们还在等
F-22s, we're still waiting.
快走！
Move out!
来了！
Incoming!
载弹发射 目标绿色
Weapons armed. Status green.
走 快走！
Run! Move!
第二波来了
Second wave's on approach.
那是什么？小心！
What is that? Break off!
2号 锁定 干掉他！
Two, get a lock! Pop that guy!
盯住他 别让他跑了
Stay on him. Keep him in your sights.
把他带走！
Take him out!
2号中弹！
Two's down!
我要杀了你！
I'll kill you!
火种源是我的！
Mine! All Spark!
山姆！快把能量体塞入我的胸膛！
Sam! Put the Cube in my chest! Now!
山姆！
Sam!
不 山姆！
No, Sam!
别开火
Hold up.
你逼得我别无选择 兄弟
You left me no choice, brother.
山姆 我欠你一条命
Sam, I owe you my life.
我们都欠你的情
We are in your debt.
擎天柱 我们没能救他
Prime, we couldn't save him.
哦 爵士
Oh, Jazz.
我们失去了一位杰出的战友
We lost a great comrade,
但也结识了新的战友
but gained new ones.
谢谢大家
Thank you, all of you.
我们敬佩你们的勇敢
You honor us with your bravery.
我有话要说 长官
Permission to speak, sir?
请讲吧 老朋友
Permission granted, old friend.
你能说话了？
You speak now?
我希望和男孩呆在一起
I wish to stay with the boy.
如果他也同意
If that is his choice.
同意
Yes.
总统已经下令…
Gentlemen, the President has ordered…
将第七区组织解散
Sector Seven be terminated…
处理掉外星人尸体
and the remains of the dead aliens disposed of.
罗伦提恩海沟有7英里深
The Laurentian Abyss is seven miles below sea level,
地球上最深的地方
deepest place on our planet.
这个深度的…
The massive depth and pressure there,
极高压与极低温
coupled with subfreezing temperatures,
会把尸体压扁
would crush and entomb them,
不留任何蛛丝马迹
leaving no evidence.
火种源被摧毁
With the All Spark gone,
我们已经无法回到自己的星球
we cannot return life to our planet.
造化弄人
And fate has yielded its reward,
我们的新家叫做地球
a new world to call home.
我们和这里的人共同生活 藏在他们眼皮之下
We live among its people now, hiding in plain sight,
也在悄悄地地保护他们
but watching over them in secret,
等待 保护
waiting, protecting.
我目睹了他们的勇气
I have witnessed their capacity for courage.
尽管和我们来自不同世界
And though we are worlds apart,
但像我们一样 他们也不可貌相
like us, there's more to them than meets the eye.
我是擎天柱
I am Optimus Prime…
在这里召唤所有
and I send this message to any surviving Autobots
在宇宙中流亡的汽车人
taking refuge among the stars.
我们在这里
We are here.
我们在等待
We are waiting.
你们知道最近这个地方有…
Can you shed any light on the recent,
所谓的外星人活动吗？
so-called alien activity in the area?
你知道吗？我想…
Do you know what? I think that…
如果真有外星人…
if there was some sort of an alien
- 入侵… - 嗯
- infestation… - Yeah
我们的政府
They, the government,
会第一个让我们知道
would be the first to let you know.
政府会让我们知道的
The government would let us know.
- 我是说 这里是美国 - 对
- I mean, this is America. - Yeah.
正因为那样 我们才知道 我们生活在一片自由的土地上
You know, that's how we know we live in a free land,
因为没有秘密
because there's no secrets.
他们会说“嘿 快找掩护”
They'd say, "Hey! Duck and cover."
你的头和电视里面…
Your head is kind of…
有点不一样大
of a different size than it is on television.